<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Marlow's Listener</title>
 <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-05-05T22:56:11-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://technocrat.githup.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Richard Careaga</name>
   <email>public@careaga.net</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Parse date string</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/timezone/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/timezone</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# timezone.py
# exemplar
from datetime import datetime
from dateutil.parser import parse
from dateutil import tz

# The input isn&#39;t something that Python recognizes as a date
s = &quot;Mon Aug 15 21:17:14 GMT 2011&quot;     #start off with a string
d = parse(s)                           #convert it to a datetime object

# parse doesn&#39;t capture timezone information, so we need to specify
GMT = tz.gettz(&#39;UTC&#39;)                  #label for GMT
Beijing = tz.gettz(&#39;Asia/Shanghai&#39;)    #label for localtime

there = d.astimezone(GMT)              #express the datetime object in the GMT(UTC) zone
here = d.astimezone(Beijing)           #express it local zone

print(here)

print(there)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fun with stats</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/normal/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/normal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/statfact&quot;&gt;@StatFact&lt;/a&gt; -. The transform y = arcsine(sqrt(x)) can make proportion data approximately normally distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Land of the Free</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/jim-crow/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/jim-crow</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although the United States accounts for about 5 percent of the world’s population, it houses nearly 25 percent of the world’s prison population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1GY7Te7&quot;&gt;Hon.Jed S. Rakoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bread and Circuses</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/gopfield/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/gopfield</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At this stage, the important thing to remember is that there are really two spectacles taking place: a high-stakes horse race for the Republican nomination, and a circus held on the infield of the track. Although the events run concurrently, and are ostensibly geared toward the same end, they shouldn’t be confused with one another. One is a serious political contest. The other is a sideshow, designed to amuse the spectators, give the media something to cover, and further the ambitions, varied as they are, of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Cassidy in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1zKpsPr&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Seven Pillars of Data Wisdom</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/datawisdom/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/datawisdom</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical functions produce measures, not analyses
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Being able to produce a measure or graph a function is not the same as understanding the result.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;See perennial best-seller &lt;em&gt;How to Lie with Statistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s even easy to fool yourself&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t assume that the data at hand necessarily is all you should be looking at.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GIGO&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What the data &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; tell us&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finding the right ballpark&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quick and dirty but approximately right beats exactly wrong&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Teasing out the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; questions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confirmatory Data Analysis
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is the theory that the data are supposed to test?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The null hypothesis and negative proof&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finding the right statistical tool&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Interpreting the result&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Survey of Tests
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Parametric&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Non-parametric&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Tests to Models
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Parsimony as a guiding principle&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Types of predictive modelling&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dangers of overfitting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sensitivity, edge cases, game changers and other qualifiers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reproducibility
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Checklists&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Standardized reports&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version control&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data snapshots&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Seeding&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Underselling as career insurance&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Balance between bottom lines and supporting detail&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Importance of visualization&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keeping the gory details to technical appendices&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Confronting “so what?”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>BOOM!</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/boomers/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/boomers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wall-street-journal-warns&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/aging-baby-boomers-bring-drug-habits-into-middle-age-1426469057&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; warns&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers0.png&quot; alt=&quot;The shocking headline&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As the 76 million baby boomers reach late middle age, older adults are abusing drugs, getting arrested for drug offenses, and dying from drug overdoses at increasingly higher rates. The sharp increase in overdose deaths among older adults in particular is “very concerning,” says Wilson Compton, deputy director for the National Institute on Drug Abuse. The rate of death by accidental drug overdose for people aged 45 through 64 increased 11-fold between 1990, when no baby boomers were in the age group, and 2010, when the age group was filled with baby boomers, according to an analysis of CDC mortality data. That multiple of increase was greater than for any other age group in that time span. The surge has pushed the accidental overdose rate for these late middle age adults higher than that of 25- to 44-year-olds for the first time. Experts say the drug problem among older Americans has been brought on because a generation with a predilection for mind-altering substances is growing older in an era of widespread opioid analgesic abuse. Opioid analgesics are the drug most often involved in overdoses, followed by antianxiety medication, cocaine, and heroin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/aging-baby-boomers-bring-drug-habits-into-middle-age-1426469057&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; (2015-03-16) (&lt;em&gt;paywalled&lt;/em&gt;) by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zushaelinson&quot;&gt;Zusha Elinson&lt;/a&gt;, quoted by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/RjWvMu&quot;&gt;American Pharmacists Association&lt;/a&gt;. This &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/C1dQEk&quot;&gt;graphic&lt;/a&gt; (reproduced below) from the article illustrates the claims made in the headline and extract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stirring-the-teacup-to-make-a-tempest&quot;&gt;Stirring the Teacup to Make a Tempest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reporter, on Twitter as @&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zushaelinson&quot;&gt;ZushaElinson&lt;/a&gt;, describes himself there as focusing on criminal justice, which is also reflected in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/search/aggregate.html?KEYWORDS=Zusha+Elinson&amp;amp;SEARCHQUERY_PARSER=bylineAND&amp;amp;START_INDEX=21d&quot;&gt;WSJ bylines&lt;/a&gt;. But it is not lack of experience in science writing that troubles me with this reporting; &lt;em&gt;the facts do not show that the newly minted seniors have been drug abusers since high school and are disproportionately dying of drug overdoses even when they aren’t being arrested for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As defined in the article, boomers were born from 1946 to 1964. We mostly graduated from high school on schedule from 1964 to 1982. Currently, the youngest of us is 50 and the oldest 69. In 1990 we were 26 to 44; in 2000, 36 to 54; and in 2010, 46-64.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;busted&quot;&gt;Busted!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with the claim in the graphic that &lt;em&gt;the rate for drug arrests for older adults (45-64) has increased dramatically as boomers have aged&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compared to What?&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;What Was Happening?&lt;/em&gt; are two unanswered questions. From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/aus9010.pdf&quot;&gt;Bureau of Justice Statistics&lt;/a&gt; we have answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the rates of drug arrests for &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; age group went up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the rates in 1990 include no boomers in the 45-64 year old bracket; the rates in 2000 include some but not all boomers; and 2010 is all boomers. The difference between the 1990 (black, solid) and 2010 (black, dotted) shows that compared to our immediate predecessors, born 1929-1945, boomers in their mid to late 40s had higher arrest rates, but the generational difference narrows greatly by the mid-50s and looks little different by 60. (Note, also, that the data series cuts off at age 64; too few seniors are busted for use to make the data very interesting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, from 1990 to 2010, the US population grew by 13.1%. The &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; of drug possession/use arrests grew by 80% and the &lt;em&gt;rate&lt;/em&gt; was 46% higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There were 80% more arrests for drug possession or use in 2010 (1,336,530) than in 1990 (741,600). Between 1990 and its peak in 2006, the arrest rate for drug possession or use increased 75% (figure 37). The arrest rate declined between 2006 and 2010, ending in 2010 at 46% above its 1990 level and at a level similar to those seen between 1997 and 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/aus9010.pdf&quot;&gt;Bureau of Justice Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the actual numbers represented by these rates? For 2010, the 45-64 age bracket had about 153,000 arrests for drug possession/use. Out of a population in that bracket of 63.8 million. &lt;strong&gt;In other words, the “dramatic increase” reflects less than 1/4 of 1% of all boomers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for drug arrests as support for the supposition that boomer counterculture types have carried their habits into late middle age as reflected by arrest statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teen-drug-use&quot;&gt;Teen Drug Use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boomers were druggies in their senior years of high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cited source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Johnston, L. D., O’Malley, P. M., Bachman, J. G., Schulenberg, J. E. &amp;amp; Miech, R. A. (2014). &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1Po1zP5&quot;&gt;Monitoring the Future&lt;/a&gt; national survey results on drug use, 1975–2013: Volume I, Secondary school students. Ann Arbor: Institute for Social Research, The University of Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;puts things in better perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Until 1978, the proportion of 12th graders involved in any illicit drug use increased steadily, primarily because of the increase in marijuana use (see Figures 5-1 to 5-4a). About 54% of the classes of 1978 and 1979 reported using at least one illicit drug during the prior 12 months, up from our first observation of 45% in the class of 1975. Between 1979 and 1984, however, the proportion who reported using any illicit drug during the prior year dropped by one to three percentage points annually until 1985, when there was a brief pause in the decline. In 1986 the decline resumed, with annual prevalence dropping significantly to 27% by 1992, exactly half the peak level experienced in 1979. As with marijuana, and largely due to marijuana, the annual prevalence of using any illicit drug then increased substantially during the relapse in the drug epidemic, from 27% in 1992 to 42% by 1997, after which it leveled for a few years before falling modestly to 36% by 2007. It remained at 37% in both 2008 and 2009, increased nonsignificantly to 38% in 2010, and then to 40% in 2011, where it remains in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-drug-use-currently&quot;&gt;What About Drug Use Currently?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/NSDUHresultsPDFWHTML2013/Web/NSDUHresults2013.pdf&quot;&gt;Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration&lt;/a&gt; gives this view&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Unsurprisingly, drug use goes down with age. There is a story about the difference between boomers and their immediate precedessors, but the story’s illustration points us toward the distant past&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to show boomers as &lt;em&gt;a generation with a prediliction for drugs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better question is &lt;strong&gt;what’s happening now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1ckNwOi&quot;&gt;2012 National Survey on Drug Use and Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boomers toke. Younger boomers toke more than older boomers. Leading edge boomers were fairly steady in their 2002-2012 intake. &lt;em&gt;And guess who’s playing catch-up?&lt;/em&gt; The immediate pre-boomers. (In the single digits, in all cases.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the same source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Nonmedical use of prescription drugs (basically painkillers and seditives) show a similar pattern, with the leading edge boomers converging on their slightly older cousins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cocaine, heroin, hallucigens and inhalents are also covered, but account for very little of the total usage of illicit drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buckets-got-a-hole-in-it&quot;&gt;Bucket’s Got a Hole in It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary and graphic in the story give the most prominence to a sharp rise in drug overdose rates for the 45-64 year old group.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
The first thing to notice is the use of overlapping categories: the red line for 45-64 and the black line for 55-74. Why? Cynically, it looks as if the tenor of the presentation is that whenever boomers join a line, rates shoot up. But if you look at the end points for the red and orange lines, there is no difference (less than 0.01 per 100,000) between the all-boomer and no-boomer groups. Also note that the boomers in the 70s had far lower OD rates than young adults since 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once more, there is more useful data from the same agency as the article cites. &lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1ckNUfO&quot;&gt;Chen, Hedegaard and Warner&lt;/a&gt; provide this view into the important category of opioid overdose deaths
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other class of drugs involved in overdose deaths is benzodiazapens (Valium(TM) and its decscendants), usually in conjunction with opioids. Although cocaine and heroin overdoses can lead to death, the low usage in the boomer age group is expected to be reflected in relatively low numbers of deaths, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-my-beef&quot;&gt;What’s My Beef?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the missing piece tying it all together&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The continuing increases in illicit drug use among adults aged 50 or older have important implications for substance use treatment and for the health care delivery system in general. The higher rates of use, coupled with the increasing size of the older adult population in the United States as the baby boom cohort ages, suggest a greater need for health care providers to consider illicit drug use among their older patients while also diagnosing and treating their health problems. Additionally, it has been projected that the number of adults aged 50 or older who would need alcohol or drug treatment would increase from 2.8 million (annual average) in 2002 to 2006 to 5.7 million in 2020 (Han, Gfroerer, Colliver, &amp;amp; Penne, 2009b). The results of the 2012 NSDUH are consistent with this projection, showing an estimated 4.0 million older adults currently needing substance use treatment, including 0.4 million persons needing treatment only for illicit drugs, 3.2 million needing treatment only for alcohol, and 0.4 million needing treatment for both alcohol and illicit drugs.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1ckNwOi&quot;&gt;2012 National Survey on Drug Use and Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am growing cynical in my old age. I could easily imagine this piece as the opening salvo of a &lt;em&gt;Dump Social Security and Medicare&lt;/em&gt; campaign by the WSJ with the theme &lt;em&gt;they will just blow it on drugs, anyway&lt;/em&gt;. First we get it from our parents and now our kids. Karmic justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps. As a generation we have much to answer for. &lt;em&gt;But let us answer to the facts&lt;/em&gt;, which were mal-reported in the WSJ article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my gripes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stereotyping: everyone &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; that the early boomers had a reputation for “doing drugs,” so it follows that the generation born 1946-1964 actually &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; do drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of discrimination: there are drugs and there are drugs—lumping heroin and cocaine, which can be mortally dangerous with marijuana, which has always been harmful almost exclusively because it was forbidden tells us nothing useful about what challenges people moving into late middle age and old age face.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of context: drug use doesn’t exist in a societal vacuum
Missing elephants: 3.6 million adults over 50 need treatment for alcohol abuse; 400 thousand need treatment for drug abuse not including alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is already too easy to create clickbait in digital media. We need reporting from the old-line media, in its variety of world views, that does what it is supposed to do. Journalism: looking at the facts critically, not stretching them to decorate the headline. Copy editors have become an endangered species and I fear editors will soon follow. Reporters need both; I worry that they are getting neither.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The eternal *who*?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/who/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/who</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We perceive the light reflected from ten million leaves and see the pattern &lt;em&gt;trees&lt;/em&gt;. We perceive the air on our skin or the dinner in our gut and feel the pattern &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;. But me should be &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;, an ecosystem of bacteria and viruses to which we each are the primordial forest. Nor is industrial agriculture missing – we suppress or enhance fertility, apply pesticides and fertilizers and sprinkle fairy dust into our brains. Kill a bug, adjust pH, lower the hydraulic pressure, change the ratios of this or that to the other, we cultivate our East Eden gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the atheists among us believe in a version of the soul, even if it is not immortal. Beneath the Aristotelian accident lies a Platonic essence, our very own unique DNA. But that is a twinkling screen of flashing pixelish genes, ready to express an alternative manifestation at the drop of a protein. The chicken soup of our soul simmers in a cauldron that can, unexpectedly, serve out gazpacho or pho, dishes that nourish personae which our table companions can easily distinguish, even as we ourselves cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eco-stews of our persons imagine themselves not only accurately to perceive, appropriately to categorize and purposefully to direct the incidents of their preparation. Dinner believes it has free will, constrained solely by personal legislation it enacts. Impinging on our own gustatory illusions are enablers to be propitiated (&lt;em&gt;forgive me, Father&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;pleeaase&lt;/em&gt;) or coerced (if worldly). We believe that nothing happens without personal agency, God’s or luck, that bitch goddess, or men and women and the lesser animals, such as dogs and children who we drape with moral vestments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because we impose a pattern, however, does not create an explanation, or even a meaning. Newton’s clockwork project has no scope in Planck’s probability  waves nor in our personal determinants whose calculation falls forever beyond Moore’s Law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a result, not a cause.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Church, state and billionaires</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/pope/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/pope</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But this, too, was a minor threat. Langone was simply threatening to withhold money. Now, as the pope prepares a major encyclical on climate change, to be released this summer, the billionaires are spending a great deal of their money in a direct assault on him. They are calling in their chits, their kept scientists, their rigged conferences, their sycophantic beneficiaries, their bought publicists to discredit words of the pope that have not even been issued: “He would do his flock and the world a disservice by putting his moral authority behind the United Nations’ unscientific agenda on the climate,” they say. They do not know exactly what the pope is going to say in his forthcoming encyclical on preserving God’s creation, but they know what he will not say. He will not deny that the poor suffer from actions that despoil the earth. Everything he has said and done so far shows that Francis always stands for the poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary Wills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1I6vdI0&quot;&gt;NYRB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Poke in the eye with a sharp stick</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/insult/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/insult</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If the intent is to insult, then is it really such a shock that people could feel insulted? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1GKKRVo&quot;&gt;Vox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Brave New World</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/git-me/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/git-me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marlow has been blogging going on a score years, first on an SGI Indy and a fractional T-1, then a virtual server. Such tedious overhead. Aristophenes be damned! Onto the cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It can never be just one lie</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/01/04/beliefs/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/01/04/beliefs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;unless you have an indefinitely extensible repertoire of ways to use your candidate belief (if that is what it is) in different contexts, it is not a belief in any remotely recognizable sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Dennett, &lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reynold's Number</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2013/01/28/poem/"/>
   <updated>2013-01-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2013/01/28/poem</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have no quarrel with time.&lt;br /&gt;
I float, flow, will sink, not sync.&lt;br /&gt;
Time herself has the indifference&lt;br /&gt;
Of a schoolboy’s secret crush,&lt;br /&gt;
We stand invisible in suspense&lt;br /&gt;
That perhaps the usual rules&lt;br /&gt;
Will be suspended, in our case,&lt;br /&gt;
And the surprise will be more time,&lt;br /&gt;
Time long after we weary of it&lt;br /&gt;
As we wearied of childhood and&lt;br /&gt;
Its fabled happiness of endless&lt;br /&gt;
August cut off from recess.  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
