<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Marlow's Listener</title>
 <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-08-24T22:03:47-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://technocrat.githup.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Richard Careaga</name>
   <email>public@careaga.net</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Intimidate and dominate or exterminate</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/08/03/domination/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/08/03/domination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Six police officers couldn’t get a mentally ill prisoner to bend her knees, so she could be placed in a transfer chair. So, they shocked the 5’3”, 130 pound black woman four times and stopped her heart, following which, presumably, they achieved compliance with their lawful order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As reported in &lt;a href=&quot;http://wapo.st/1gG8LMz&quot;&gt;WaPo&lt;/a&gt;, this is just the outcome to be expected in applying 50,000 volts to a severely agitated person or giving anyone four applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanley Milgram would not be surprised that people who are given permission to apply force past any point of persuasion would not hesitate to keep cranking the dial. The officers could not break her will, so they broke her heart, literally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This represents another problematic aspect of standard police doctrine, which is the application of non-lethal force to attain voluntary compliance of a subject. Most people choose to surrender rather than endure increasing amounts of pain. For that portion of those to be subdued, it is certainly preferable to the use of deadly force. (Doctrine is also shoot-to-kill, not disable.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But another portion of those to be subdued have no will to overcome, because they are permanently or temporarily cut-off from their rationality due to chronic mental illness or to the effects of drugs. No amount of pain will suffice to bring these to submission. They must be physically disabled. A low-tech way to do this, in use for over 2,000 years, is to entangle the subject in a net. A bolo can also be effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An appropriate control tactic to the situation, however, is hindered by the Universal Hammer approach of continuing to apply the same method, in this case using a Taser, hoping that it will work this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would think that two officers holding a small subject’s shoulders, one sitting on her lap, two strapping in her legs and one in reserve would have been a preferable approach. You have to wonder if the method that was used had its origins more in punishing defiance.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Universal Hammer</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/08/02/steele/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/08/02/steele</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;fewer-questions-needed-for-the-same-answer&quot;&gt;Fewer questions needed for the same answer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/thecounted&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; is compiling a list of 2015 police involved deaths. Everyone knows of the focus over the past year on the role of racial animus in the many high-profile incidents. But other, less prominent cases summarized by that reporting illustrate other aspects of policing that deserve attention. This is not an &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; lives matter essay and solving the types of problems discussed here will do little to address racial problems in policing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;autumn-steele-34-year-old-white-female&quot;&gt;Autumn Steele, 34 year-old white female&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 6, 2015, a lot was happening in the front yard of 104 North Garfield Avenue in Burlington, Iowa. Snow covered the yard, and most  of the family was outside amidst shouting and pummeling. City Police Officer Jesse Hill was trying to separate the parents, the 4-year old son was crying and young Sammy rushes outside to come to their aid. He jumps on Hill’s back, who turns around, draws his weapon, fires at Sammy, falls backwards and fires again. One shot kills Autumn and that shot or the other injures Sammy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sammy is a German shepard. He survived his injuries and escaped conviction as a vicious animal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Officer Hill &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dps.state.ia.us/commis/pib/Releases/2015/DesMoines_County_Attorney_Ruling_OIS_Burlington.pdf&quot;&gt;was not prosecuted.&lt;/a&gt;The county attorney concluded that Hill acted reasonably in shooting at Sammy to avoid injury and the facts would not support a charge of involuntary manslaughter or any greater offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://c.ymcdn.com/sites/www.nacanet.org/resource/resmgr/Docs/NACA_Guidelines.pdf&quot;&gt;The National Animal Care and Control Association Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; recommend that police officers receive training to better respond to canine threats with non-lethal alternatives. According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acolodd.com&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to memorializing police and animal control officers killed in the line of duty, animals have been directly reponsible for deaths of &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; officers in last 50 years. One died as a result of injuries sustained in a fall while attempting to control a dog; the other was killed by a loose cow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;balancing-the-tough-question&quot;&gt;Balancing, the tough question&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Steele, the inadvertant victim of Officer Hill’s shots is not a sympathetic figure. News accounts and the county attorney’s report show that she was the aggressor and had come straight home from a court hearing prohibiting her from returning unsupervised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That shouldn’t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The preschooler could just as easily have been shot. Or the husband. Or a bystander or neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application of deadly force against a threat to a police officer is secondarily a decision to expose others to harm equal to or greater than the harm that the officer faces. No one wants to be bitten, especially after asking the owners to control the dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no one wants to die to prevent a dog bite, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A police officer who is taking a careful shot at an active shooter to prevent her own or another’s safety is taking a considered risk. It may turn out well (the would-be school shooter is killed before unleasing fire on students and staff). It may turn out poorly (the bullet ricochets off the shooter’s weapon and hits a bystander). Everyone should join the officer in mourning the accident just as they should join in celebrating a successful shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A police officer, like one in Hill’s situation, who is taking shots while falling is taking an unconsidered risk. &lt;em&gt;Shoot first, think later&lt;/em&gt; makes it impossible to weigh the risk avoided against the risk created. It is also unlikely that any amount of training is going to be effective to make split-second life-and-death decisions while falling to the ground which minimize the risk of doing more harm than good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Police doctrine that promotes deadly force to prevent injuries that are not life threatening leads inevitablly to promoting deadly force to pre-empt or deter threats. Bystander casualties become &lt;em&gt;collateral damage&lt;/em&gt;, at most regrettable but secondary to the requirements of force protection. Its exact analogy is deadly force in the form of high-speed pursuit. If a felon fleeing at 125mph presents a grave danger to public safety, it is hard to see that having him followed by one or more police officers reduces that threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The police are not physicians. They do not proceed from the premise of a first duty to &lt;em&gt;do no harm.&lt;/em&gt; But we should want them to proceed from a duty to &lt;em&gt;do least harm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Anticipation</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/30/anticipate/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/30/anticipate</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After midsummer we have a belated feeling as if we had all been idlers, and are forward to see in each sight and hear in each sound some presage of the fall, just as in middle age man anticipates the end of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Jul. 30, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Southern heritage needs no stars and bars</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/24/jr-johnson/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/24/jr-johnson</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wilkes County is all hills, ridges, woods and underbrush, full of pin oaks, sweet-gum maples, ash, birch, apple trees, rhododendron, rocks, vines, tin roofs, little clapboard places like the Mount Olive Baptist Church, signs for things like Double Cola, Sherrill’s Ice Cream, Eckard’s Grocery, Dr. Pepper, Diel’s Apples, Google’s Place, Suddith’s Place and—yes!—cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Wolfe in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1OCwgBf&quot;&gt;Esquire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Bible says so</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/17/ars-lingua/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/17/ars-lingua</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the Almighty himself condescends to address mankind in their own language, his meaning, luminous as it must be, is rendered dim and doubtful by the cloudy medium through which it is communicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madison, &lt;em&gt;Federalist&lt;/em&gt; 37&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Thematic Mapping in R without the Tears</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/15/thematic-quickstart/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/15/thematic-quickstart</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By: Richard Careaga &lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/technocrat.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; style=&quot;height: 25px;&quot; /&gt; 2015-07-15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;quick-start-edition&quot;&gt;Quick Start Edition&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A current, working installation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://rproject.org&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to install required packages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with &lt;a href=&quot;http://rproject.org&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding of directory paths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-youll-see&quot;&gt;What you’ll see&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The default basemap of the contiguous 48 states and the District of Columbia
 &lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-07-15-default.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The same map with an uncolored background  &lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-07-15-white.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The basemap with states shown by population with the default continuous scale and color scheme
 &lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-07-15-pop.default.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The basemap in four alternative discrete color scales with a neutral palette and polyconic projection
&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-07-15-scaling.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-up&quot;&gt;Next up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be preparing a detailed explanation of how this works and recommendations for deciding when this type of presentation works well and what data transforms to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am unable to answer questions relating to the use of this code under Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;algorithms&quot;&gt;Algorithms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rpubs.com/danielkirsch/styling-choropleth-maps&quot;&gt;Interval scales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1LPM7hc&quot;&gt;Population U.S. Census&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1IZgFLV&quot;&gt;Cartographic Boundary File U.S. Census&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/geo/reference/ansi_statetables.html&quot;&gt;State postal codes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;r-packages&quot;&gt;R Packages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baptiste Auguie (2012). gridExtra: functions in Grid graphics. R package version 0.9.1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=gridExtra&quot;&gt;gridExtra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roger Bivand (2015). classInt: Choose Univariate Class Intervals. R package version 0.1-22.&lt;a href=&quot;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=classInt&quot;&gt;classInt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roger Bivand, Tim Keitt and Barry Rowlingson (2015). rgdal: Bindings for the Geospatial Data Abstraction Library. R package version 1.0-4 &lt;a href=&quot;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=rgdal&quot;&gt;rgdal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;D. Kahle and H. Wickham. ggmap: Spatial Visualization with ggplot2. The R Journal, 5(1), 144-161.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.r-project.org/archive/2013-1/kahle-wickham.pdf&quot;&gt;ggmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duncan Temple Lang and the CRAN team (2015). RCurl: General Network (HTTP/FTP/…) Client Interface for R. R package version 1.95-4.7. &lt;a href=&quot;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=RCurl&quot;&gt;RCurl&lt;/a&gt; 
Hadley Wickham and Francois Romain. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hadley/dplyr&quot;&gt;dplyr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Erich Neuwirth (2014). RColorBrewer: ColorBrewer Palettes. R package version 1.1-2. &lt;a href=&quot;http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=RColorBrewer&quot;&gt;RColorBrewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;R Core Team (2015). R: A language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna, Austria. &lt;a href=&quot;http://r-project.org&quot;&gt;grid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;H. Wickham. ggplot2: elegant graphics for data analysis. Springer New York, 2009.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://had.co.nz/ggplot2/book&quot;&gt;ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-1&quot;&gt;Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cartographic Boundary File: Download latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.census.gov/geo/maps-data/data/cbf/cbf_state.html&quot;&gt;cartographic boundary file for states&lt;/a&gt; from the U.S Census, currently &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.census.gov/geo/tiger/GENZ2014/shp/cb_2014_us_state_5m.zip&quot;&gt;cb_2014_us_state_5m.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/geo/reference/ansi_statetables.html&quot;&gt;State postal codes&lt;/a&gt;, copy to csv, as follows:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
	Alabama,01,AL
	Alaska,02,AK
	Arizona,04,AZ
	Arkansas,05,AR
	California,06,CA
	Colorado,08,CO
	Connecticut,09,CT
	Delaware,10,DE
	District of Columbia,11,DC
	Florida,12,FL
	Georgia,13,GA
	Hawaii,15,HI
	Idaho,16,ID
	Illinois,17,IL
	Indiana,18,IN
	Iowa,19,IA
	Kansas,20,KS
	Kentucky,21,KY
	Louisiana,22,LA
	Maine,23,ME
	Maryland,24,MD
	Massachusetts,25,MA
	Michigan,26,MI
	Minnesota,27,MN
	Mississippi,28,MS
	Missouri,29,MO
	Montana,30,MT
	Nebraska,31,NE
	Nevada,32,NV
	New Hampshire,33,NH
	New Jersey,34,NJ
	New Mexico,35,NM
	New York,36,NY
	North Carolina,37,NC
	North Dakota,38,ND
	Ohio,39,OH
	Oklahoma,40,OK
	Oregon,41,OR
	Pennsylvania,42,PA
	Rhode Island,44,RI
	South Carolina,45,SC
	South Dakota,46,SD
	Tennessee,47,TN
	Texas,48,TX
	Utah,49,UT
	Vermont,50,VT
	Virginia,51,VA
	Washington,53,WA
	West Virginia,54,WV
	Wisconsin,55,WI
	Wyoming,56,WY
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;license&quot;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2015, Richard Careaga&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the “Software”), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED “AS IS”, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;r-code&quot;&gt;R Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/technocrat/ddf573cd461790d0c026#file-thematic&quot;&gt;gist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!---
rbitlyApi(&quot;YOUR_KEY_HERE&quot;)
pop_source &lt;- links_Shorten(&quot;https://www.census.gov/popest/data/national/totals/2014/files/NST_EST2014_ALLDATA.csv&quot;)$url
--&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Descent of Man</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/15/descent/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/15/descent</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The youth gets together his materials to build a bridge to the moon, or perchance a palace or temple on the earth, and at length the middle-aged man concludes to build a wood-shed with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Jul. 15, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The tyranny of the story</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/12/narrative/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/12/narrative</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;@worrydream: Narrative inherently embraces simple causes, personal agency, single perspective, limited context. A medium for empathy won’t be stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>AI Needs to Take an Intentional Stance</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/08/dogsmind/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/08/dogsmind</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To understand the story of the Three Little Pigs, one must comprehend what each of the characters knows. For a machine to replicate this understanding, it needs to recognize these individual sets of characters’ knowledge. It needs a single set to represent the pig’s knowledge of the world, another for the wolf’s, along with a representation of the mental state the wolf is trying to get the pig into — the deception. These contexts can be layered infinitely, and Fahlman is building a system that contains them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel Wilkinson in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nxt.fm/1dKyq4s&quot;&gt;Narratively&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Grexit and Keynes' other insight</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/05/greferendum/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/05/greferendum</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even if the no vote prevails, it’s our responsibility not to re-enact a Treaty of Versailles in the eurozone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;French economy minister, Emmanuel Macron in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1NGxI4D&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Numerical manifestations</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/04/game-of-life/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/04/game-of-life</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Barricelli saw his computer organisms as a blueprint of life—on this planet and any others. “The question whether one type of symbio-organism is developed in the memory of a digital computer while another type is developed in a chemical laboratory or by a natural process on some planet or satellite does not add anything fundamental to this difference,” he wrote. A month after Barricelli began his experiments on the IAS machine, Crick and Watson announced the shape of DNA as a double helix. But learning about the shape of biological life didn’t put a dent in Barricelli’s conviction that he had captured the mechanics of life on a computer. Let Watson and Crick call DNA a double helix. Barricelli called it “molecule-shaped numbers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert Hackett in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1ChAjl8&quot;&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nature</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/07/02/nature/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/07/02/nature</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nature is reported not by him who goes forth consciously as an observer, but in the fullness of life. To such a one she rushes to make her report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, Jul 3, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Take this hammer</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/29/on-business/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/29/on-business</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In my experience nothing is so opposed to poetry— not crime— as business. It is a negation of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; Jun. 29, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Summer's best</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/26/roseslillies/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/26/roseslillies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We now have roses on the land and lilies on the water,— both land and water have done their best,— now just after the longest day. Nature says, “You behold the utmost I can do.” And the young women carry their finest roses on the other hand. Roses and lilies. The floral days. The highest, intensest color belongs to the land, the purest, perchance, to the water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; Jun. 26, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deep in the heart of Texas</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/22/texas/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/22/texas</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rep. Dan Flynn’s bill exempting Texas from daylight saving time was sidelined amid concerns that refusing to roll back the clocks could leave Texans choosing between church and watching Dallas Cowboys games on fall Sundays. Also dropped was Sen. Donna Campbell’s proposal banning the Alamo from falling under the control of the United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1TJ1Hhd&quot;&gt;TPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Momento</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/22/momento/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/22/momento</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life passes into pages if it passes into anything,” he once wrote. It has nowhere else to go. The pages, at least, will have some permanence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James Statler, quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1dbxQfE&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Grexit in a nutshell</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/20/grexit/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/20/grexit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In truth, this has never been a fiscal crisis at its root; it has always been a balance of payments crisis that manifests itself in part in budget problems, which have then been pushed onto the center of the stage by ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1TDLTw0&quot;&gt;Krugman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cyclides</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/19/clover-days/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/19/clover-days</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These are the clover days. The light of June is not golden but silvery, not a torrid but somewhat temperate heat. See it reflected from the bent grass and the under sides of leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt; Jun. 19, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>GI Jane</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/12/GI-Jane/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/12/GI-Jane</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here indeed is a major difference between people and ants: where we send our young men to war, ants send their old ladies. No moral lesson there, unless you are looking for a less expensive form of elder care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E.O. Wilson, &lt;em&gt;The Meaning of Human Existence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On derp</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/08/derp/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/08/derp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve already mentioned one telltale sign of derp: predictions that just keep being repeated no matter how wrong they’ve been in the past. Another sign is the never-changing policy prescription, like the assertion that slashing tax rates on the wealthy, which you advocate all the time, just so happens to also be the perfect response to a financial crisis nobody expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yet another is a call for long-term responses to short-term events – for example, a permanent downsizing of government in response to a recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1HWtPV7&quot;&gt;Krugman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A muse of fire</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/08/bicameral/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/08/bicameral</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The book sets its sights high from the very first words. “O, what a world of unseen visions and heard silences, this insubstantial country of the mind!” Jaynes begins. “A secret theater of speechless monologue and prevenient counsel, an invisible mansion of all moods, musings, and mysteries, an infinite resort of disappointments and discoveries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julian Jaymes, quoted by Veronique Greenwood in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1G7xgdi&quot;&gt;Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mythic</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/07/belmont/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/07/belmont</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He was bouncing down the lane as if jumping from one trampoline to another, and no one was going to catch him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Drape in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1Jx3l2f&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Poetry from deafness</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/06/2015-06-06-deafness/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/06/2015-06-06-deafness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Only in the realm of mishearing — at least, my mishearings — can a biography of cancer become a biography of Cantor (one of my favorite mathematicians), tarot cards turn into pteropods, a grocery bag into a poetry bag, all-or-noneness into oral numbness, a porch into a Porsche, and a mere mention of Christmas Eve a command to “Kiss my feet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oliver Sachs in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1G1AzCI&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Touchdown in a horserace</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/05/nash-equilubria/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/05/nash-equilubria</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Betting on the flip of a coin involves high risk, but the potential outcomes and probability are known. “Uncertainty is when you can’t know all the outcomes or the probability with which each potential outcome will occur,” he said. “This is deep uncertainty.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yanis Varoufakis, quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1HQrlaA&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The weight on our lives</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/05/2015-06-05-insensate/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/05/2015-06-05-insensate</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;when you think about what people are actually undergoing in our civilization, you realize it’s a very grim thing to be a modern human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell in conversation with Bill Moyers, &lt;em&gt;The Power of Myth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Withering non-flation</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/04/smackdown/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/04/smackdown</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And a few years after I published that paper, the BoJ put it to the test with an 80 percent rise in the monetary base that utterly failed to move inflation expectations. In general, Japanese experience gave us plenty of reason to realize that macroeconomics changes at the zero bound. So it’s still a puzzle that so many macroeconomists tried to apply non-liquidity-trap logic in 2009 — and just embarrassing that they’re still doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1dPBnS4&quot;&gt;Krugman&lt;/a&gt;, in which he also smacks his buddy upside the head in one of his famous &lt;em&gt;ideas are more important&lt;/em&gt; than personalities  mini-Phillipics.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Daycare Costs and Unexamined Assumptions</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/04/day-care/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/04/day-care</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The rise of data journalism has not been accompanied by a rise in thoughtful analysis. I saw this again the other day from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1G0IoIZ&quot;&gt;Vox&lt;/a&gt; and I was annoyed by using a map just to show percentages (why not a table?) and then began noticing other problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the costs come from a source that gives separate estimates for an infant and a four-year old at day-care centers and the article-lite doesn’t say which it used to calculate the percentages of median income that costs represent. Worse, it uses median &lt;em&gt;household&lt;/em&gt; income, when data for &lt;em&gt;families&lt;/em&gt; is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it does not stratify the data by race. There are differences, large differences, between the cost profiles for everyone and for individual classifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following series of maps divides costs into high, medium and low percentages of family income for each of the following groups: all races, non-Hispanic white, Hispanic, African American, Asian American and Native American. The percentages are based on the reported costs of infant day care in a day care center as a portion of &lt;em&gt;median&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;family&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a similar all-in presentation to the one that &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1G0IoIZ&quot;&gt;Vox&lt;/a&gt; used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-06-04-day-care_all_races.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shows a group of expensive states, colored dark blue, in the Pacific states and Nevada, Colorado and Kansas, the Upper Midwest, North Carolina and most of the urban Northeast states. (Omitted, due to scale, is the District of Columbia, which is even more expensive.) This group has costs ranging from about 15.7% to 21% of median family income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intermediate group, colored a lighter blue, includes Montana and Wyoming, most of the remainder of the Midwest, plus the Southwest, Texas, Oklahoma and Florida, plus Connecticut and the rural New England states. This group has costs ranging from about 13.4% to 15.7% of median family income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining group, colored lightest blue, of states with the daycare costs that consume the least proportion of family income includes most of the South, Idaho and Utah, the Dakotas and New Jersey. This group has costs ranging from about 10% to 13.4% of median family income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, this only addresses my first set of criticisms. I’ve shown the mapped data more appropriately and I’ve specified the data used in the calculations. But what about the second criticism, blindness that not all communities have similar median family incomes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what the situation looks from the perspective of white, non-Hispanic families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-06-04-day-care_white_non_hispanic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most-intermediate-least expensive states follow a similar patterns with a few shifts. &lt;strong&gt;But in each case the buckets are lower.&lt;/strong&gt; The most expensive states only require up to about 18% of median (white, non-Hispanic) family income, compared to about 21% for all families. The intermediate states are similar and the least expensive states require as little as about 8.4% of median family income, compared to about 10% for all families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation for Asian American families is similar to that of white, non-Hispanic families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-06-04-day-care_asian.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big difference is that the most expensive states are up to about 22% of median (Asian-American) family income, compared to about 18% for white, non-Hispanic. There are some differences in which states are the least or most expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Hispanic, African-American and Native American families, the pictures are quite different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-06-04-day-care_hispanic.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-06-04-day-care_african_american.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-06-04-day-care_native_american.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these groups are divided into similar collections of states in the three categories. And the &lt;strong&gt;least&lt;/strong&gt; expensive category for each requires the same proportion of median family income as the &lt;strong&gt;most&lt;/strong&gt; expensive categories for white, non-Hispanic and Asian-American families. The &lt;strong&gt;most&lt;/strong&gt; expensive category for each group requires &lt;em&gt;twice&lt;/em&gt; the percentage of median family income, up to 45%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to keep sight of the limitations of the data and the ways in which ratios interact. Consider a family moving from an intermediate cost state to a higher cost state. &lt;em&gt;Only&lt;/em&gt; if its income does not rise will its day-care expense ratio worsen. These maps, then, show the interaction between costs in each state and incomes in each state, which can move in synch or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it is unrealistic to expect that minority families in these three groups are spending nearly half their pre-tax&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:ss&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:ss&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; income on child care. The cost data are averages, and within each state there are more expensive day care centers and less expensive day care centers. We can assume that minority families use the least expensive centers or resort to home-based day care to bring costs within manageability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the extent that costs of care in centers reflect quality of care, the result might be facilities that are less safe, staffed by less experienced or less well trained staff in those centers within the means of those families than at the market average cost facilities. &lt;em&gt;All other things being equal,&lt;/em&gt; children receiving care in low-cost centers should be expected to have poorer outcomes than their contemporaries at market-average facilities. To the extent that those early childhood experiences have later effects on childhood development they are unlikely to be positive. This can only be thought of as another potential contributor to the &lt;strong&gt;cycle of poverty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shouldn’t think of day care merely as a place to store children during business hours any more than we should think that way of schools. Children are people, too, my friend. Like corporations they lack the vote and the proportion of the electorate struggling to meet the costs of child care in any election cycle is probably not enough to swing results. In a political system of competing interest groups, minority children are among the least influential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:ss&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Although families with lower incomes may escape income taxes, payroll taxes reduce the portion of family income available to pay daycare. As a result, the average costs in the most expensive states may represent closer to half of take-home pay. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:ss&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Not-on-my-watchism</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/03/metadata/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/03/metadata</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I came in with a healthy skepticism about these programs,” Mr. Obama said. “My team evaluated them. We scrubbed them thoroughly. We actually expanded some of the oversight, increased some of the safeguards. But my assessment and my team’s assessment was that they help us prevent terrorist attacks. And the modest encroachments on the privacy that are involved in getting phone numbers or duration without a name attached and not looking at content, that on net, it was worth us doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Obama, quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1G6zhYB&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oversight, safeguards and compliance measures do not deter true believers on a devine mission any more than they deter traders.  The Freedom Act (newspeak term) does nothing more than allow the President and his state security apparatus (polite term for the secret police) to claim that formerly they were stretching a law that did not permit free roving warrants, they are now stretching one that does.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A favorable reference to the Devil</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/02/rand/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/02/rand</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Big Data Kool-Aid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But for all his grandstanding—he has been selling anti-N.S.A. T-shirts, and tweeting up a “Stand with Rand” storm—Paul had sensible things to say in that speech. One of them was a reminder that, if the government has suspicions, it has plenty of ways to get a real warrant without collecting everyone’s phone records: “I think we spend so much money on people for whom there is no suspicion that we don’t have enough time and money left to go after the people who would actually harm us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Davidson in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1dcul9c&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>=> FLT</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/06/01/fermat/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/06/01/fermat</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And, it seemed, he never elaborated elsewhere. After his death, his son Samuel published a new edition of Arithmetica that included all of the notes that Fermat had made in its margins. These observations, typically stated without proof, posed an irresistible challenge. Within a few years, readers had confirmed every one—except the statement about higher-dimension Pythagorean triples. It was the “last” unsubstantiated claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Brown in [Nautilus]&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Whither Westphalia?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/31/westphalia/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/31/westphalia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Far from marking the “end of imperialism”, what we are witnessing today, a century after the implosion of the Ottoman empire, is its resurgence. In this new scramble for the Middle East, we are witnessing the petty sultans of the region’s crumbling states trying to hold on to their micro-empires; non-state armed groups trying to usurp them; Iran and the emerging powers of the Gulf seeking to expand their spheres of influence; and the US’ long-standing hegemony being challenged by the new-old kid on the block, Russia, and newcomer China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Khaled Diab in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1FNEtPx&quot;&gt;Al Jazeera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Modesty</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/31/modesty/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/31/modesty</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So numerous indeed and so powerful are the causes which serve to give a false bias to the judgment, that we, upon many occasions, see wise and good men on the wrong as well as on the right side of questions of the first magnitude to society. This circumstance, if duly attended to, would furnish a lesson of moderation to those who are ever so much persuaded of their being in the right in any controversy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hamilton, &lt;em&gt;Federalist № 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Repose of illness</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/28/spring-fever/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/28/spring-fever</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lying in bed with aching joints and a fever,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wracking up plugs of phlegm,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the patient suffers the annual spring chest cold&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the voice descends to the lower register,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so does the normal awareness of time, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;like Einstein’s traveler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever it was, last week or next, will have to wait&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The faint cares of taxes and insurance pass through brief notice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vague ambition to re-read, again, the page of the open book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;arises and likewise fades&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Life has no script</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/28/mantel/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/28/mantel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I say to the cast, “Henry didn’t know he was going to have six wives. Each time he thought, here’s the girl for me.” People smile, but they grasp the essential thing. The characters don’t know their own fates. They can’t learn a lesson from themselves, and draw a moral. We have scripts, but they don’t. They are trapped in 50 years of improvisation, called life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hilary Mantel in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1Rr6tO6&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Recombinant</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/28/dylan/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/28/dylan</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is there any thing whereof it may be said, See, this is new?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ecclesiastes 1:10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m glad for my songs to be honored like this. But you know, they didn’t get here by themselves. It’s been a long road and it’s taken a lot of doing. These songs of mine, they’re like mystery stories, the kind that Shakespeare saw when he was growing up. I think you could trace what I do back that far. They were on the fringes then, and I think they’re on the fringes now. And they sound like they’ve been on the hard ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/music/posts/la-et-ms-grammys-2015-transcript-of-bob-dylans-musicares-person-of-year-speech-20150207-story.html&quot;&gt;Dylan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 25 centuries, between the Preacher and the Mystery Tramp, a long skein of wisdom has always had it that novelty is superficial, the human condition is unchanging and meaning is ever uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Were we ever to see something truly new instead of merely different, we would neither recognize nor comprehend it. An alien comes to Earth. It wanders around seeing nothing it recognizes as like anything it knew. And it wanders invisibly down city streets, through suburban malls and along country roads, impinging on our senses but unregistered by our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no punchline without a setup.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gaming the system</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/27/nash/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/27/nash</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These days, political scientists, evolutionary biologists, and even government regulators are obliged to grasp best-response equilibria and other aspects of game theory. Whenever a government agency is considering a new rule—a set of capital requirements for banks, say, or an environmental regulation—one of the first questions it needs to ask is whether obeying the rules leads to a Nash equilibrium. If it doesn’t, the new policy measure is likely to prove a failure, because those affected will seek a way around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Cassidy in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1HLLeVC&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Struggle of the particular with the universal</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/26/tolstoy/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/26/tolstoy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This violent contradiction between the data of experience, from which he could not liberate himself, and which, of course, all his life he knew alone to be real, and his deeply metaphysical belief in the existence of a system to which they must belong, whether they appear to do so or not, this conflict between instinctive judgement and theoretical conviction – between his gifts and his opinions – mirrors the unresolved conflict between the reality of the moral life, with its sense of responsibility, joys, sorrows, sense of guilt and sense of achievement – all of which is nevertheless illusion – and the laws which govern everything, although we cannot know more than a negligible portion of them – so that all scientists and historians who say that they do know them and are guided by them are lying and deceiving – but which nevertheless alone are real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isaiah Berlin, &lt;em&gt;The Hedgehog and the Fox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Millenials in historical context</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/26/balzac/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/26/balzac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Doing his utmost, deploying all his energy, a young man setting out from zero can wind up after ten years somewhere below where he started. Today, talent needs the kind of luck that favors the incompetent; in fact, if a skilled man rejects the vile arrangements that bring success to rampant mediocrity, he will never get on at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Balzac, &lt;em&gt;Z. Marcas&lt;/em&gt; (tr. Linda Asher, Carol Cosman and Jordan Stump)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You, Robot</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/24/robots/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/24/robots</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have been dreaming of robots since Homer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Mendholsohn in&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1Gx9MAg&quot;&gt;NYRB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The view from 270 million years ago</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/23/2015-05-23-ginkgo/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/23/2015-05-23-ginkgo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-23-ginkgo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The wisdom in knowing where to stop</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/22/wisdom/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/22/wisdom</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You know, we have a tremendous amount of information about this subject, but there is a place where the information stops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell in conversation with Bill Moyers, &lt;em&gt;The Power of Myth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On the other hand</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/21/french/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/21/french</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the great French gift for producing courteous children is more than met by the rage and misery that most French children feel about the discipline necessary to produce the manners (it’s why they riot at eighteen);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Toobin in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1LgwkV1&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Typical RMBS tape fields</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/20/tape/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/20/tape</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From approximately October 2005 through June 2007, the following form of information is typical of what issuers provided in connection with sales of residential mortgage backed securities in the United States issued by private institutions. This example is from a filing by an affiliate of Washington Mutual Bank and is available as an &lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1c11dAN&quot;&gt;EDGAR filing&lt;/a&gt; from the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. At the time of the filing, I was the principal lawyer involved in securitizations for Washington Mutual Bank and its affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Field&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;WMMSC Loan&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;unique identifier&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Loan type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;30-year fixed rate mortgage loans&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Gross Coupon&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;rate of interest paid by borrower&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Net Coupon&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;rate of interest paid to investor after deduction of servicing fees&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Orig Bal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the US dollar principal balance at origination&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Curr bal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the unpaid principal balance as of June 1, 2007&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Sched bal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the unpaid principal balance as of June 1, 2007 after taking into account servicer advances&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;P and I&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;scheduled monthly payment for principal and interest&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Lien&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;first-lien mortgages or deeds of trust&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;LTV&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;loan-to-value ratio at origination based on Orig Bal and the property valuation used for making the loan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;CBLTV&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;current balance loan-to-value ratio based on the Curr bal and the same valuation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Occupancy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Primary residence of borrower, Second home of borrower, Investment&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Proptype&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Planned Unit Development, Single Family Detached, Condominium, 4-unit apartment building, townhouse, 2-unit apartment building, cooperative apartment&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Units&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;number of dwelling units&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Orig term&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;number of months from origination to scheduled maturity&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Balloon&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;whether a balloon payment feature is included&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Note Date&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the date on which the loan was funded&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Rem Term&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;number of months until the expiration of the Orig term&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;First Pay date&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the first day of the month in which the first payment was received&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Maturity Date&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the date on which the loan is scheduled to be fully paid&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;City&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;municipality in which the mortgaged property is located&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;State&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;state in which the mortgaged property is located&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Zip&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;postal code in which the mortgaged property is located&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Purpose&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Purchase Cash-out refinance Rate-term refinance&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;MI Comp&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;type of mortgage payment insurance&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;PMI%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the percentage of the original principal balance insured&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;App Val&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the property valuation used in making the loan&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;PPP Term&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;number of months the loan is subject to a prepayment penalty&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;PPP Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;no key available&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;PPP String&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;no key available&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;IO Period&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;number of months that only payments of interest are due&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Doctype&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;credit information provided by borrower Reduced/Low/Express/Stated, Full/Alternative/Streamlined, No Documentation/No Income-No Assets, No Ratio of Income to Debt&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Assets verified&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;whether borrower’s assets were verified&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;DTI Back end&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;the ratio of the borrower gross monthly income to existing and proposed payments of principal and interest&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;FICO&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;credit score&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;SP Appraisal Type&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;no key&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Self Employed&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;whether borrower self employed&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reductionist</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/20/chem/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/20/chem</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Better living through &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1dm6KDA&quot;&gt;chemistry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>When history catches up with memory</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/19/lewiston/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/19/lewiston</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whatever shape Liston was in, he did turn out to be child-friendly, fulfilling Michael Feldman’s wish for him to visit his school. “I was the first Jewish student in the school, and for show-and-tell, I brought a black former heavyweight champion,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1EhNnAC&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dissociative reality</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/19/dissociative/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/19/dissociative</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Read other people’s myths, not those of your own religion, because you tend to interpret your own religion in terms of facts— but if you read the other ones, you begin to get the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph Campbell in conversation with Bill Moyers, &lt;em&gt;The Power of Myth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Obama is no LBJ</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/18/race/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/18/race</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Who can be the Nixon to go to our internal China?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have never been among those who thought President Obama should “say more” about Ferguson, because I don’t believe most of the people who elected him actually want to “hear more.” What these people have never tired of hearing is another discourse on the lack of black morality or on the failings of black culture. It saddens me to see the president so sincerely oblige.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ta-Nehisi Coates in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theatln.tc/1JTlgNj&quot;&gt;Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Shock resistance</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/17/shaw/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/17/shaw</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And yet, instead of exclaiming “Send this inconceivable Satanist to the stake,” the respectable newspapers pith me by announcing “another book by this brilliant and thoughtful writer.” And the ordinary citizen, knowing that an author who is well spoken of by a respectable newspaper must be all right, reads me, as he reads Micah, with undisturbed edification from his own point of view. It is narrated that in the eighteen-seventies an old lady, a very devout Methodist, moved from Colchester to a house in the neighborhood of the City Road, in London, where, mistaking the Hall of Science for a chapel, she sat at the feet of Charles Bradlaug for many years, entranced by his eloquence, without questioning his orthodoxy or moulting a feather of her faith. I fear I small be defrauded of my just martyrdom in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G.B. Shaw, &lt;em&gt;Preface to Man and Superman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Landscape, with effigy</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/17/effigy/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/17/effigy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-17-effigy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Survivor bias</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/16/suvivor/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/16/suvivor</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With great force he argues that only those orders or decisions issued by the commanders now seem particularly crucial (and are concentrated upon by historians) which happened to coincide with what later actually occurred; whereas a great many other exactly similar, perfectly good orders and decisions, which seemed no less crucial and vital to those who were issuing them at the time, are forgotten because, having been foiled by unfavourable turns of events, they were not, because they could not be, carried out, and for this reason now seem historically unimportant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isaiah Berlin, &lt;em&gt;The Hedgehog and the Fox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Memories of tastes past</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/16/sobranie/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/16/sobranie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was 19 and a &lt;em&gt;college man&lt;/em&gt; (even then, an outdated expression), I took it into my head to smoke a pipe. Not, as some, but not many, of my coursetemporaries were smoking, as a crucible for &lt;em&gt;Cannibus sativa,&lt;/em&gt; but for its &lt;strong&gt;truly&lt;/strong&gt; addictive distant cousin, &lt;em&gt;Nicotiana tabacum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a period of trial and error, I learned, to the dismay of my roommates, of the inverse relationship between &lt;em&gt;room note&lt;/em&gt; and actual taste. Thus, I left behind the aromatic blends that smelled like vanilla insense and moved on to the more manly blends, that smelled something like burning tires but had a robust, smooth taste that I could enjoy all day without becoming satiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first station was a blend still made, albeit with Cypriot, rather than true, Syrian, Latakia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-16-raparee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was perhaps more refined than my palette, for I soon gravitated to a deeper, mellower blend&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-16-black-mallory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That in turn was but a waystation before I turned to the blend that would carry me through my appointed score years of smoking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-16-sobranie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This produced a smoke that was almost chewy, like a single-malt scotch. It was my many pipe a day companion until the time came that I entered a smoke free setting just when my self diected promise to give up the habit came due. Since that day, when Blessèd St. Ronald is said to have been working miracles, my chimney has been cold, save for the occasional cigar during the Clinton years.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Future strangers</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/strangers/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/strangers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And I thought he was foolish, this man in his seventies, who had no idea what you must do. But the fanaticism of my twenties shocks me now. As I feared it would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annie Dillard, &lt;em&gt;The Writing Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Secret police have always relied on secret laws</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/sec-215-1/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/sec-215-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1KRZVnH&quot;&gt;The Section 215 Wrecking Ball - The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Congress, of course, has been known to do nothing. Rampant game-theorizing joined with senatorial incompetence may mean that June 1st will come and nothing will be done. If there is one thing that the Senate is adept at, it’s missing deadlines. This is a hard one to hide from, though, even for these legislators. We’re used to asking whether Congress matters; in this case, the question here is whether Congress’s laws matter, either. If they don’t, we’re not left with much in Washington but a wrecking ball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Davidson&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Effluent Society</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/robo/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/robo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;John Kenneth Galbraith was within a letter of being right&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The disappearance of jobs has not ushered in a new age of leisure, as social theorists predicted uneasily in the 1950s. Would the masses utilize their freedom from labor in productive ways, such as civic participation and the arts, or would they die of boredom in their ranch houses? Somehow, it was usually assumed, they would still manage to eat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1PLZZqs&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Object lesson</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/object/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/object</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The idea that objective observation can be performed only by an observer totally free of subjectivity involves an ideal of inhuman purity which we now recognise as being, fortunately, unattainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ursula K. Le Guin, &lt;em&gt;The Wave in the Mind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My cat Lua</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/lua-cat/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/lua-cat</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been dabbling in the hipster lanaguage Lua, which you have to be cool even to have heard about. Its claim to fame is minimalism. It has one data type, called a table and I found myself wanting to combine two or more of them à la cat (concatenate). WTF, there is no built-in way to do this? Incredulity began to lift when I discovered that neither was there a built-in way to even print tables. As a public service for the benefit of other pilgrims, here is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   --cat.lua concatenate tables
    function cat( ... ) -- append 1D tables
        local List = require &#39;pl.List&#39; -- penlight library
        local args = {...}
        local l = List()
        for i=1, #args do
            l:extend(args[i])
        end
        return l
    end
    --[[Example
    a = {
        &quot;gala&quot;,
        &quot;cameo&quot;,
        &quot;jazz&quot;
    }
    o = {
        &quot;seville&quot;,
        &quot;valencia&quot;,
        &quot;navel&quot;
    }
    g = {
        &quot;concord&quot;,
        &quot;thompson&quot;,
        &quot;muscat&quot;
    }
    f = cat(a,o,g)
    {gala,cameo,jazz,seville,valencia,navel,concord,thompson,muscat}
    --]]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Truth be told</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/hedgehogs/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/hedgehogs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Plato, Lucretius, Pascal, Hegel, Dostoevsky, Nietzsche, Ibsen, Proust are, in varying degrees, hedgehogs; Herodotus, Aristotle, Montaigne, Erasmus, Molière, Goethe, Pushkin, Balzac, Joyce are foxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isaiah Berlin, &lt;em&gt;The Hedgehog and the Fox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Armour propre</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/15/armour-propre/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/15/armour-propre</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The potentates of this world are sufficiently apt to consider themselves as possessed of an inherent superiority which gives them a right to govern and makes mankind their own; and this infatuation is almost every where fostered in them by the creeping sycophants about them and the language of flattery which they are continually hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Discourse on the Love of our Country&lt;/em&gt; by Richard Price, delivered on Nov. 4, 1789, at the Meeting-House in the Old Jewry, to the Society for Commemorating the Revolution in Great Britain&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nothing funny</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/14/nothing-funny/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/14/nothing-funny</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that so far he seems to be a terrible candidate. He couldn’t keep his “I’m-my-own-man” mantra going through the spring. He over-babbled at a private gathering. He didn’t know how to answer the Iraq question, which should have been the first thing he tackled on the first day he ever considered that he might someday think for even a minute about running for president.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is obviously a problem for the Bush camp, but it’s a big one for the nation’s army of concerned citizens, too. There are lots of Americans who are not going to vote Republican next year, but who nevertheless have found some comfort in the idea that Jeb Bush would almost certainly be the Republican nominee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gail Collins &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1E7usIJ&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>H. economicus?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/14/h-economicus/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/14/h-economicus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When we treat each other as intentional systems, we are similarly finessing our ignorance of the details of the processes going on in each other’s skulls (and in our own!) and relying, unconsciously, on the fact that to a remarkably good first approximation, people are rational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Dennett, &lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mrs. Freddy Eynsford Hill</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/14/eynsford/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/14/eynsford</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Galatea never does quite like Pygmalion: his relation to her is too godlike to be altogether agreeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G.B. Shaw, &lt;em&gt;Pygmalian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>No one here but the plutocrats</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/14/cover/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/14/cover</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is one of the key features of early 21st century political campaigns and political life in general that every political figure requires a chorus of dedicated partisans who lay down the equivalent of covering fire in their leader’s defense. Sometimes this happens with a political figure who attracts intense loyalty. But that’s seldom required. Partisans on both sides of the political divide will generally rush to the defense of almost any political figure on their team, even if the person isn’t terribly well liked or even if they’re getting grief for something that is pretty hard to defend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1HjhXRR&quot;&gt;TPM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dick Lit</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/13/dick-lit/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/13/dick-lit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My progress on &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1IBzaou&quot;&gt;Books That Literally All White Men Own&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑ = unowned, read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☒ = owned, read&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;◻︎ = owned, unread&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†  = unowned, unlikely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑︎	1. Shogun, James Clavell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	2. Slaughterhouse-Five, Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	3. A Confederacy of Dunces, John Kennedy Toole&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;◻	4. Infinite Jest, David Foster Wallace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	5. A collection of John Lennon’s drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	6. A Farewell to Arms, Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☒	7. The first two volumes of A Song of Ice and Fire, George R.R. Martin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	8. God Is Not Great, Christopher Hitchens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☒	9. Catch-22, Joseph Heller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	10. I Hope They Serve Beer In Hell, Tucker Max&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	11. Atlas Shrugged, Ayn Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	12. The Man Who Mistook His Wife For A Hat, Oliver Sacks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	13. The Catcher in the Rye, J.D. Salinger&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	14. The Godfather, Mario Puzo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	15. The Great Gatsby, F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	16. Lolita, Vladimir Nabokov&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	17. Fight Club, Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☒	18. The Master and Margarita, Mikhail Bulgakov&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	19. The Da Vinci Code, Dan Brown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	20. The Grapes of Wrath, John Steinbeck&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	21. The Stand, Stephen King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	22. The Girl With the Dragon Tattoo, Stieg Larsson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	23. The Naked and the Dead, Norman Mailer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	24. Tuesdays With Morrie, Mitch Albom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	25. It’s Not About the Bike, Lance Armstrong (definitely under the bed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	26. Who Moved My Cheese?, Spencer Johnson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	27. Portnoy’s Complaint, Philip Roth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	28. Seabiscuit, Laura Hillenbrand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	29. John Adams, David McCullough&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	30. Ragtime, E.L. Doctorow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	31. Lucky Jim, Kingsley Amis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	32. America: The Book, Jon Stewart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	33. The World Is Flat, Thomas Friedman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	34. The Tipping Point, Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	35. The Curious Incident of the Dog In the Night-Time, Mark Haddon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	36. Exodus, Leon Uris (if Jewish)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	37. Trinity, Leon Uris (if Irish-American)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	38. The Road, Cormac McCarthy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	39. Marley &amp;amp; Me, John Grogan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	40. Freakonomics, Steven D. Levitt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	41. The Rainmaker, John Grisham&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	42. Patriot Games, Tom Clancy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	43. Dragon, Clive Cussler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	44. Guns, Germs, and Steel, Jared Diamond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	45. The Agony and the Ecstasy, Irving Stone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	46. The 9/11 Commission Report&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	47. The Spy Who Came In From the Cold, John le Carre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	48. Rising Sun, Michael Crichton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	49. A Walk in the Woods, Bill Bryson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	50. Airport, Arthur Hailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	51. Rich Dad, Poor Dad, Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	52. Burr, Gore Vidal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	53. Angela’s Ashes, Frank McCourt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	54. The Wheel of Time, Robert Jordan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	55. Into Thin Air, Jon Krakauer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	56. Into the Wild, Jon Krakauer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	57. Cryptonomicon, Neal Stephenson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	58. Godel, Escher, Bach, Douglas Hofstadter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	59. The World According to Garp, John Irving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	60. A Brief History of Time, Stephen Hawking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	61. The Tin Drum, Gunter Grass&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☒	62. On the Road, Jack Kerouac&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	63. Lord of the Flies, William Golding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☒	64. The Lord of the Rings, JRR Tolkien&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	65. The Bonfire of the Vanities, Tom Wolfe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	66. Beowulf, the Seamus Heaney translation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	67. Rabbit, Run, John Updike&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	68. The Satanic Verses, Salman Rushdie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;◻	69. The Complete Sherlock Holmes, Sir Arthur Conan Doyle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	70. The Big Sleep, Raymond Chandler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	71. One Flew Over the Cuckoo’s Nest, Ken Kesey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	72. A Clockwork Orange, Anthony Burgess&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	73. House of Leaves, Mark Danielewski&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	74. The Call of the Wild, Jack London&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	75. Gravity’s Rainbow, Thomas Pynchon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;☑	76. I, Claudius, Robert Graves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	77. The Civil War: A Narrative, Shelby Foote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	78. American Psycho, Bret Easton Ellis (a glaring omission from the original, pointed out by Naomi Fry)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;†	79. Life, Keith Richards&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dark Leaf</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/13/dark-leaf/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/13/dark-leaf</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-13-dark-leaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cry wolf</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/13/cry-wolf/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/13/cry-wolf</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The way the public hears about conservation issues is nearly always in the mode of ‘^Beloved_Animal Threatened With Extinction’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stewart Brand, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1FrZrVv&quot;&gt;Aeon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Silent compacts</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/13/compacts/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/13/compacts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We were, however, doomed, and knew it. The constitution of parents and children may, like the British one, be unwritten, but, as the Brits point out, that doesn’t make it less enforceable or authoritative. The unwritten compact that governs family life says somewhere that children who have waited long enough for a dog and want one badly enough have a right to have one. I felt as the Queen must at meeting an unpleasant Socialist Prime Minister: it isn’t what you wanted, but it’s your constitutional duty to welcome, and pretend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Gopnik in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1EF4e0W&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Does the Pope have the authority to sanction gay marriage?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/13/catholic/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/13/catholic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;OK, although I’m trained as a civil lawyer, I’m certainly no learned doctor of the Canon Law of the Catholic Church. For that reason, I’m going to be taking at face value many statements published by ostensibly authoritative sources concerning Church teachings regarding questions of Papal Primacy and LGTG issues, which the Church often describes as “homosexuality.” I discuss what appear to be the principal statements that would have to be walked back and how those might present problems with inconsistencies with related areas. I won’t be speculating about internal Church constituencies and the pushback that might result from a change in the Church’s positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To gratify the curiosity of the seekers after hidden motivations, I am a old, heterosexual, married male, baptized in the Catholic Church, but never I confessed or took communion. I am atheist after many years as an agnostic, of Mexican and Irish descent. Any readers who find that relevant should probably move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of Doctrine and Papal Authority&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/lz49n&quot;&gt;United States Conference of Catholic Bishops&lt;/a&gt; has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/lz49n&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/a0oE4&quot;&gt;Catechism&lt;/a&gt; is an authoritative source of Church doctrine. &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/X3rUuw&quot;&gt;American Bishops&lt;/a&gt; have long enjoyed a reputation for power and independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is the doctrinal or teaching authority of the Catechism?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Catechism is part of the Church’s official teaching in the sense that it was suggested by a Synod of Bishops, requested by the Holy Father, prepared and revised by bishops and promulgated by the Holy Father as part of his ordinary Magisterium.  Pope John Paul II ordered the publication of the Catechism by the Apostolic Constitution, Fidei Depositum, on October 11, 1992. An apostolic constitution is a most solemn form by which popes promulgate official Church documents. The new Code of Canon Law, for example, was promulgated by the Apostolic Constitution, Sacrae Disciplinae Leges.  In Fidei Depositum, Pope John Paul II said, “The Catechism of the Catholic Church, which I approved June 25th last and the publication of which I today order by virtue of my Apostolic Authority, is a statement of the Church’s faith and of catholic doctrine, attested to or illumined by Sacred Scripture, the Apostolic Tradition, and the Church’s Magisterium. I declare it to be a sure norm for teaching the faith and thus a valid and legitimate instrument for ecclesial communion.”  John Paul II also stated that the Catechism “is given as a sure and authentic reference text for teaching Catholic doctrine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The term “ordinary Magisterium” appears to have been a term of some &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/QtVv1f&quot;&gt;debate&lt;/a&gt; or confusion in the years following Vatican II. However, the term now is used in contradistinction to “extraordinary Magisterium”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;a distinction is made between the “ordinary” and “extraordinary” &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/pCl7sK&quot;&gt;Magisterium&lt;/a&gt;, emphasizing the importance of the first, which is permanent and ongoing, while the second, which is expressed in definitions, could be called exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In fact, the extraordinary Magisterium is seldom invoked. The latest was in 1950 by Pope Pius XII in the Bull Munificentissimus on the Assumption. Although the Pope may (and perhaps has a duty to) act in communion with the Bisphops in the Magisterium of the Church, he acts on his own authority&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the extraordinary papal Magisterium, whose definitions are unreformable per se, and not from the consent of the Church” (ex sese, non autem ex consensu ecclesiae). This means that these definitions do not need the consent of the bishops in order to be valid, neither an antecedent consent, nor a consequent consent, “since they are pronounced with the assistance of the Holy Spirit, promised to him in blessed Peter, and therefore they need no approval of others, nor do they allow an appeal to any other judgment”. (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/pCl7sK&quot;&gt;Magisterium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The same principle applies to the exercise of the Pope’s ordinary Magisterium – consultation and the Pope’s authority to establish, infallibly, on his own authority when pronouncing non-definitional “doctrine concerning faith and morals” that require the inward assent and outward obedience of the faithful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These are truths about God in himself and in his creative and redeeming work; the human person and the world in their creaturely status and destiny according to the design of Providence; eternal life and earthly life itself in its basic demands regarding truth and goodness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The area of truths that the Magisterium can definitively teach includes those principles of reason that are not contained in the truths of faith but are closely related to them. In actual fact, both in the past and today, the Church’s Magisterium, especially the Roman Pontiff’s, preserves these principles and continually rescues them from the obfuscation and distortion they suffer under pressure from partisan viewpoints and bad habits well established in cultural models and currents of thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/pCl7sK&quot;&gt;Magisterium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/a0oE4&quot;&gt;Catechism&lt;/a&gt; makes this clear.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\882 The Pope, Bishop of Rome and Peter’s successor, “is the perpetual and visible source and foundation of the unity both of the bishops and of the whole company of the faithful.”402 “For the Roman Pontiff, by reason of his office as Vicar of Christ, and as pastor of the entire Church has full, supreme, and universal power over the whole Church, a power which he can always exercise unhindered.”403&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;402 &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/et2T&quot;&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt; 23.
403 &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/et2T&quot;&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt; 22; cf. &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/7XSUC&quot;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt; 2,9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\23. This collegial union is apparent also m (sic) the mutual relations of the individual bishops with particular churches and with the universal Church. The Roman Pontiff, as the successor of Peter, is the perpetual and visible principle and foundation of unity of both the bishops and of the faithful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/et2T&quot;&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But the college or body of bishops has no authority unless it is understood together with the Roman Pontiff, the successor of Peter as its head. The pope’s power of primacy over all, both pastors and faithful, remains whole and intact. In virtue of his office, that is as Vicar of Christ and pastor of the whole Church, the Roman Pontiff has full, supreme and universal power over the Church. And he is always free to exercise this power. The order of bishops, which succeeds to the college of apostles and gives this apostolic body continued existence, is also the subject of supreme and full power over the universal Church, provided we understand this body together with its head the Roman Pontiff and never without this head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/et2T&quot;&gt;LG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\2. In this Church of Christ the Roman pontiff, as the successor of Peter, to whom Christ entrusted the feeding of His sheep and lambs, enjoys supreme, full, immediate, and universal authority over the care of souls by divine institution. Therefore, as pastor of all the faithful, he is sent to provide for the common good of the universal Church and for the good of the individual churches. Hence, he holds a primacy of ordinary power over all the churches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\9. In exercising supreme, full, and immediate power in the universal Church, the Roman pontiff makes use of the departments of the Roman Curia which, therefore, perform their duties in his name and with his authority for the good of the churches and in the service of the sacred pastors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/7XSUC&quot;&gt;CD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conclusion: If Church’s position on same-sex relations has not been set definitionally by extraordinary Magisterium, the Pope has the power to change it in the exercise of his ordinary Magisterium.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/cwRSy3&quot;&gt;Current Doctrine&lt;/a&gt; in the Catechism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chastity and homosexuality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\2357 Homosexuality refers to relations between men or between women who experience an exclusive or predominant sexual attraction toward persons of the same sex. It has taken a great variety of forms through the centuries and in different cultures. Its psychological genesis remains largely unexplained. Basing itself on Sacred Scripture, which presents homosexual acts as acts of grave depravity,141 tradition has always declared that “homosexual acts are intrinsically disordered.”142 They are contrary to the natural law. They close the sexual act to the gift of life. They do not proceed from a genuine affective and sexual complementarity. Under no circumstances can they be approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\2358 The number of men and women who have deep-seated homosexual tendencies is not negligible. This inclination, which is objectively disordered, constitutes for most of them a trial. They must be accepted with respect, compassion, and sensitivity. Every sign of unjust discrimination in their regard should be avoided. These persons are called to fulfill God’s will in their lives and, if they are Christians, to unite to the sacrifice of the Lord’s Cross the difficulties they may encounter from their condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\2359 Homosexual persons are called to chastity. By the virtues of self-mastery that teach them inner freedom, at times by the support of disinterested friendship, by prayer and sacramental grace, they can and should gradually and resolutely approach Christian perfection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\141 Cf. &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/vLepEO&quot;&gt;Gen 191-29&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/vZTrbM&quot;&gt;Rom 124-27&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/5KjHHi&quot;&gt;1 Cor 6,10&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/pB7qt0&quot;&gt;1 Tim 1,10&lt;/a&gt;.
\142 &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nVZNJb&quot;&gt;CDF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/BMbRxI&quot;&gt;Persona humana&lt;/a&gt; 8.
\143 &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nufJP&quot;&gt;FC&lt;/a&gt; 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/BMbRxI&quot;&gt;Persona humana&lt;/a&gt; is a declaration on certain questions concerning sexual ethics issued by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nVZNJb&quot;&gt;CDF&lt;/a&gt;,which  is the Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith, informally know as the Inquisition. No specific references are given to pronouncements; I have linked to the latest relevant guidance. &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nufJP&quot;&gt;FC&lt;/a&gt; is Familiaris Consortio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In short, it is not a sin to &lt;strong&gt;be&lt;/strong&gt; gay, only to have gay sex. Gay Catholics should be chaste, that is, celibate. That, of course, is a hard sell for many people, especially in light of the further teaching on masturbation&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\2352 By masturbation is to be understood the deliberate stimulation of the genital organs in order to derive sexual pleasure. “Both the Magisterium of the Church, in the course of a constant tradition, and the moral sense of the faithful have been in no doubt and have firmly maintained that masturbation is an intrinsically and gravely disordered action.”138 “The deliberate use of the sexual faculty, for whatever reason, outside of marriage is essentially contrary to its purpose.” For here sexual pleasure is sought outside of “the sexual relationship which is demanded by the moral order and in which the total meaning of mutual self-giving and human procreation in the context of true love is achieved.”139&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\138 &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nVZNJb&quot;&gt;CDF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/BMbRxI&quot;&gt;Persona humana&lt;/a&gt; 9.
\139 &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nVZNJb&quot;&gt;CDF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/BMbRxI&quot;&gt;Persona humana&lt;/a&gt; 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scripture Interpretations that Would Have to be Adjusted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/vLepEO&quot;&gt;Gen 191-29&lt;/a&gt; relates the destruction of Sodom and Gomorrah because “all the townsmen of Sodom, both young and old - all the people to the last man” asked Lot to turn over his two guests “that we may have intimacies with them.” Lot objected “I beg you, my brothers, not to do this wicked thing” and offered up his daughters as substitutes. The guests turned out to be two angels on a mission to destroy the towns. In footnote 6 to &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/rxWGXu&quot;&gt;Gen 18-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Israelite tradition was unanimous in ascribing the destruction of Sodom and Gomorrah to the wickedness of these cities, but tradition varied in regard to the nature of this wickedness. According to the present account of the Yahwist, the sin of Sodom was homosexuality (⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/UqKfYJ&quot;&gt;Genesis 19,4-5&lt;/a&gt;), which is therefore also known as sodomy; but according to Isaiah (⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/W7M81t&quot;&gt;Isaiah 1,9-10&lt;/a&gt;; ⇒ 3,9), it was a lack of social justice; Ezekiel (⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/v1VB14&quot;&gt;Ezekiel 16,46-51&lt;/a&gt;) described it as a disregard for the poor, whereas Jeremiah (⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/a8b1Sm&quot;&gt;Jeremiah 23,14&lt;/a&gt;) saw it as general immorality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lot’s position is ambiguous; it’s hard to know if his objection was to sodomy or to forcible sodomy. The trouble with the Yawist interpretation is that God appears to be in some doubt about the reports that have reached Him.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the LORD said: “The outcry against Sodom and Gomorrah is so great, and their sin so grave, that I must go down and see whether or not their actions fully correspond to the cry against them that comes to me. I mean to find out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/rxWGXu&quot;&gt;Gen 18-20/21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/vZTrbM&quot;&gt;Romans 124-27&lt;/a&gt;, the Apostle relates that God’s punishment for denying Him was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Therefore, God handed them over to impurity through the lusts of their hearts 15 for the mutual degradation of their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They exchanged the truth of God for a lie and revered and worshiped the creature rather than the creator, who is blessed forever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Therefore, God handed them over to degrading passions. Their females exchanged natural relations for unnatural, and the males likewise gave up natural relations with females and burned with lust for one another. Males did shameful things with males and thus received in their own persons the due penalty for their perversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;FN 15: In order to expose the depth of humanity’s rebellion against the Creator, God handed them over to impurity through the lusts of their hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apparently homosexuality is a punishment for the sin of denying God rather than the sin itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Timothy &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/pB7qt0&quot;&gt;1 Tim 1,10&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We know that the law is good, provided that one uses it as law, with the understanding that law is meant not for a righteous person but for the lawless and unruly, the godless and sinful, the unholy and profane, those who kill their fathers or mothers, murderers, the unchaste, practicing homosexuals, 5 kidnapers, liars, perjurers, and whatever else is opposed to sound teaching, according to the glorious gospel of the blessed God, with which I have been entrusted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\5 … Sodomites: see ⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/5KjHHi&quot;&gt;1 Cor 6,9&lt;/a&gt; and the note there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Corinthians &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/5KjHHi&quot;&gt;1 Cor 6,9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\2 3 Do you not know that the unjust will not inherit the kingdom of God? Do not be deceived; neither fornicators nor idolaters nor adulterers nor boy prostitutes nor practicing homosexuals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\ 2 9-10 A catalogue of typical vices that exclude from the kingdom of God and that should be excluded from God’s church. Such lists (cf ⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/SVZYRp&quot;&gt;1 Cor 5,10&lt;/a&gt;) reflect the common moral sensibility of the New Testament period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\ 3 9 The Greek word translated as boy prostitutes may refer to catamites, i.e., boys or young men who were kept for purposes of prostitution, a practice not uncommon in the Greco-Roman world. In Greek mythology this was the function of Ganymede, the “cupbearer of the gods,” whose Latin name was Catamitus. The term translated Sodomites refers to adult males who indulged in homosexual practices with such boys. See similar condemnations of such practices in ⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/vZTrbM&quot;&gt;Romans 1 26-27&lt;/a&gt;; ⇒ &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/pB7qt0&quot;&gt;1 Tim 1,10&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other Previous Objections to Overcome&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Christian revelation recognizes two specific ways of realizing the vocation of the human person in its entirety, to love: marriage and virginity or celibacy. Either one is, in its own proper form, an actuation of the most profound truth of man, of his being “created in the image of God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nufJP&quot;&gt;FC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;\ 8. Society owes its continued survival to the family, founded on marriage. The inevitable consequence of legal recognition of homosexual unions would be the redefinition of marriage, which would become, in its legal status, an institution devoid of essential reference to factors linked to heterosexuality; for example, procreation and raising children. If, from the legal standpoint, marriage between a man and a woman were to be considered just one possible form of marriage, the concept of marriage would undergo a radical transformation, with grave detriment to the common good. By putting homosexual unions on a legal plane analogous to that of marriage and the family, the State acts arbitrarily and in contradiction with its duties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The principles of respect and non-discrimination cannot be invoked to support legal recognition of homosexual unions. Differentiating between persons or refusing social recognition or benefits is unacceptable only when it is contrary to justice.(16) The denial of the social and legal status of marriage to forms of cohabitation that are not and cannot be marital is not opposed to justice; on the contrary, justice requires it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nor can the principle of the proper autonomy of the individual be reasonably invoked. It is one thing to maintain that individual citizens may freely engage in those activities that interest them and that this falls within the common civil right to freedom; it is something quite different to hold that activities which do not represent a significant or positive contribution to the development of the human person in society can receive specific and categorical legal recognition by the State. Not even in a remote analogous sense do homosexual unions fulfil the purpose for which marriage and family deserve specific categorical recognition. On the contrary, there are good reasons for holding that such unions are harmful to the proper development of human society, especially if their impact on society were to increase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/nVZNJb&quot;&gt;CDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For according to the objective moral order, homosexual relations are acts which lack an essential and indispensable finality. In Sacred Scripture they are condemned as a serious depravity and even presented as the sad consequence of rejecting God. &lt;em&gt;citations omitted&lt;/em&gt; This judgment of Scripture does not of course permit us to conclude that all those who suffer from this anomaly are personally responsible for it, but it does attest to the fact that homosexual acts are intrinsically disordered and can in no case be approved of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/BMbRxI&quot;&gt;Persona humana&lt;/a&gt; 8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The main reason is that, whatever the motive for acting this way, the deliberate use of the sexual faculty outside normal conjugal relations essentially contradicts the finality of the faculty. For it lacks the sexual relationship called for by the moral order, namely the relationship which realizes “the full sense of mutual self-giving and human procreation in the context of true love.” &lt;em&gt;citations omitted&lt;/em&gt; All deliberate exercise of sexuality must be reserved to this regular relationship. Even if it cannot be proved that Scripture condemns this sin by name, the tradition of the Church has rightly understood it to be condemned in the New Testament when the latter speaks of “impurity,” “unchasteness” and other vices contrary to chastity and continence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/BMbRxI&quot;&gt;Persona humana&lt;/a&gt; 9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How a Pope might imagine explaining a change in position&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Scriptural bases used to condemn homosexuality are not convincing. The outrage committed against Lot and his angelic guests can just as easily be seen as an offense against the duties of a host to protect guests. The Apostle speaks of homosexual relations being used as a &lt;em&gt;punishment&lt;/em&gt; rather than a sin in and of itself. St. Paul also speaks of the law as meant for the non-righteous and gives as an example practicing homosexuals who, among others are thought to “stand opposed to sound teaching.” But the examples include such serious matters as patricide, matricide and other murderers in the same breath with unchastity. The examples mix acts that are evil in and of themselves with those that may be wrong only because they were forbidden. In First Corinthians a similar list, the Church has already noted, is based on prevalent moral norms at the time, including a repugnance for the practice of men abusing boys, a topic of great sadness today. I think the existing Scriptural justification is open to revision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The three recent pronouncements must also be addressed. &lt;em&gt;Familiaris Consortio&lt;/em&gt; poses the difficult question: Why should the alternatives of marriage between a man and a woman, on the one hand, and the choice of virginity or chastity, on the other, be the sole means by which the Creator intended humanity to express intimate love? Much seems to depend on this argument. Guiding children away from profligacy, reducing the birth of children to those unable to care for them and pointing the way for priests to celibacy are all examples. If we were to approve of sexual acts outside of marriage in the case of homosexual relations, would that bring down the entire edifice of Church teaching on sexuality? If homosexual relations cannot lead to procreation, how can married couples be counseled to remain open to the possibility of conception each time they have relations? Would we also have to change teachings, then, on birth control? This idea of sexuality being intrinsically related to procreation as part of God’s plan and natural order is the argument made by the Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith. &lt;em&gt;Persona Humana&lt;/em&gt; cites only the “tradition of the Church” as the reason for interpreting Scripture to refer to homosexual relations as a sin, but makes the same natural law argument regarding the heterosexuality as the only natural and proper use of the sexual facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How difficult it is to change only one thing! Might it be better to review our entire understanding of “God made man in his own image” and what is natural? Would that help or hinder the faithful finding their way to God’s love? I must pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On a peak in Darien</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/12/neuron/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/12/neuron</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Christof Koch, at the Allen Institute, likens Deisseroth to Galileo, whose early improvements of the telescope afforded a huge advance in our understanding of the cosmos. Even so, like Galileo’s telescope, which opened up the immensity of space, Deisseroth’s technologies have helped reveal how little we know about the brain—what Koch calls “by far the most complex piece of organized matter in the known universe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1JFozaD&quot;&gt;The Optogenetics Breakthrough - The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>And then, a miracle!</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/12/make-believe/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/12/make-believe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fabula rasa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A reconciliation between the two conflicting requirements is effected by a resort to make-believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thorstein Veblen, &lt;em&gt;Theory of the Leisure Class&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Generation gap</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/12/gap/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/12/gap</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Truth must change her fashion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is not too much to say that no formula which expresses clearly the thought of one generation, can convey the same meaning to the generation which follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brooke Foss Westcott, D.D., D.C.L 
Bishop of Durham, Late Regius Professor of Divinity, Cambridge, and Canon of Westminster&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Combination of k items, taken n at a time</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/12/combination/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/12/combination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Very functional&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-- combo.hs
-- problem: C(k,n), where k = the integers from 1 to 9, inclusive
-- and n = 3, without regard to order, then sum the subsets
import Data.List
combinations 0 lst = [[]]
combinations n lst = do
    (x:xs) &amp;lt;- tails lst
    rest &amp;lt;- combinations (n-1) xs
    return $ x : rest
result = ( map sum (combinations 3 [1..9]))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python alternative&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import itertools
result = map(sum, itertools.combinations([1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9], 3))
for i in result: print(i)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A tale of filial defiance</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/12/bloom/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/12/bloom</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I weary of scholars neighing against Ahab, who is magnificent in his heroism. Would they have him hunt for more blubber? His chase has Job’s Leviathan in view, a quarry representing Yahweh’s sanctified tyranny of nature over man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harold Bloom,  &lt;em&gt;The Daemon Knows: Literary Greatness and the American Sublime&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Too big to fail? Us?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/11/vampires/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/11/vampires</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What was really lethal was the interaction between size and complexity. Financial institutions had become chimeras: part bank, part hedge fund, part insurance company, and so on. This complexity let them evade regulation, yet be rescued from the consequences when their bets went bad. And bankers’ ability to have it both ways helped set America up for disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1ASjuqB&quot;&gt;Krugman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Connect the dots</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/11/dots/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/11/dots</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There has been some realization that collecting and connecting dots when everything and anything looks like a dot is less than illuminating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amy Davidson in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1PCoV3B&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-11-texas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Do Nots</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/11/do-nots/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/11/do-nots</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t listen to the voice that says go for it!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t ignore the voice that says you’ll be sorry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t focus on your failures, you can always find new ways of screwing up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t expect it to be different this time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t worry about tomorrow, you’ll know it when it comes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/10/time/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/10/time</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The nature of reality that spills forth from Einstein’s physics is so much more startling than the simplistic, undergraduate-beloved shibboleth: everything is relative to subjective points of view. In Einstein’s physics, there is no passage of time, no unidirectional flow from the fixed past and toward the uncertain future. The temporal component of space-time is as static as its spatial components; physical time is as still as physical space. It is all laid out, the whole spread of events, in the tenseless four-dimensional space-time manifold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rebecca Goldstein quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1H2BUal&quot;&gt;Brain Pickings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Just a dynastic accident?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/10/scotland/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/10/scotland</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The so-called “West Lothian Question” - the thorny issue of Westminster MPs sitting in Scotland, Wales or Northern Ireland being able to have a say over matters that affect only England - will finally be settled, once and for all, with the dissolution of the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1FXZQiM&quot;&gt;The UK is now a failed state&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Magna Carta</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/10/magna-carta/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/10/magna-carta</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Considered in its immediate historical context, &lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1KzxkDf&quot;&gt;Magna Carta&lt;/a&gt; is at least as much of a property lease amendment as a constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Parliament Men</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/10/coke/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/10/coke</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-10-coke.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 Coke, &lt;em&gt;Institutes of the Laws of England&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deep in the heart of Texas</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/texas/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/texas</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everyone who operates in the public world and gets mail knows that a small percentage of the American population is completely out of its mind. It’s always been that way. The founding fathers probably received letters from people who believed King George was living in a barn down the road and spying on the local militia while disguised as a burro. The difference now, of course, is that the Internet and social media make them a lot more visible and noisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gail Collins, in.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1zNVo4W&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Purposefulness</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/purpose/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/purpose</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I proposed folk psychology as a term for the talent we all have for interpreting the people around us— and the animals and the robots and even the lowly thermostats— as agents with information about the world they act in ( beliefs ) and the goals ( desires ) they strive to achieve, choosing the most reasonable course of action, given their beliefs and desires. Some researchers like to call folk psychology “theory of mind” (or just TOM), …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The power and ease of use of folk psychology is due, I have argued, to the simplifying assumptions that enable it. It is like an idealized model in science— maximally abstract and stripped down to the essentials. I call this the intentional stance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Dennett, &lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Language is collaborative</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/language/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/language</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This linkage reveals the absorbing paradox at the heart of language’s origins. As hardwired as it is, language is a distributed object, both across the human brain and across generations of people. And it is precisely the chaotic hot-potato toss of words and grammar that yields the order and beauty that we see today. In the realm of language, as in other things, modern science is showing us that we are not the pilots of our own sealed ship, but are actors in a play, each able to contribute a verse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nautil.us/issue/24/error/the-family-that-couldnt-say-hippopotamus-rp&quot;&gt;The Family That Couldn’t Say Hippopotamus - Issue 24: Error - Nautilus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Original intent</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/intent/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/intent</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This shared property, the meaning (of the two sentences in their respective languages), or the content (of the beliefs they express), is a central topic in philosophy and cognitive science. This aboutness that, for example, sentences, pictures, beliefs, and (no doubt) some brain states exhibit, is known in philosophical jargon as intentionality , an unfortunate choice as a technical term, since outsiders routinely confuse it with the everyday idea of doing something intentionally (as in “Are your intentions honorable?”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Dennett, &lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Unarmed conflct</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/inhouse/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/inhouse</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And in corporations, not politicians but courtiers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Politics are possible in the church, as in the university, because power is dispersed and the combatants are protected from dismissal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Gopnik&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1QUUCbSr&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Connect. The. Dots.</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/dotd/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/dotd</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is there a moral here? I think it is that the world is a very complicated place, and it’s way too easy to miss what you should see even if your analytical framework is pretty decent. For me, at least, the great crisis came as a surprise but not a shock, something I didn’t see coming but not a deep problem for my sense of how the world works. Still, I do wish I’d paid more attention to the right things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1EXO06n&quot;&gt;Krugman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Current backlog</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/09/backlog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/09/backlog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100 Statistical Tests in R N.D Lewis, August 20,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1940: FDR, Willkie, Lindbergh, Hitler-the Election amid the.. Susan Dunn, September 9,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 More Fallacies Michael LaBossiere, October 19,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;40 Years of Evolution: Darwin’s Finches on Daphne Major.. Peter R. Grant, August 5,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;42 Fallacies Michael LaBossiere, October 19,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A History of the American People Paul Johnson, November 7,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A More Perfect Heaven Dava Sobel, December 29,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man James Joyce, September 24,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advanced R (Chapman &amp;amp; Hall/CRC The R Series) Hadley Wickham, January 14,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alan Turing: The Enigma: The Book That Inspired the Film.. Andrew Hodges, November 29,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Algorithms Unlocked Thomas H. Cormen, November 20,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;America’s Great Debate: Henry Clay, Stephen A. Douglas, and.. Fergus M. Bordewich, May 13,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Evolutionary Theory of Economic Change (Belknap Press) Richard R. Nelson, January 20,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Antifragile: Things That Gain from Disorder (Incerto) Nassim Nicholas Taleb, November 27,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arthur and George Julian Barnes, March 7,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bach: Music in the Castle of Heaven John Eliot Gardiner, December 13,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being Mortal: Medicine and What Matters in the End Atul Gawande, October 6,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond Outrage: What has gone wrong with our economy and our.. Robert B. Reich, May 4,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bleak House (Annotated, Illustrated) Charles Dickens, December 10,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blind over Cuba: The Photo Gap and the Missile Crisis.. Max Holland, September 24,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catastrophe 1914: Europe Goes to War Max Hastings, May 24,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catherine the Great: Portrait of a Woman Robert K. Massie, November 21,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collected Works of Edmund Burke Edmund Burke, January 19,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colorless Tsukuru Tazaki and His Years of Pilgrimage: A.. Haruki Murakami, August 11,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Command and Control: Nuclear Weapons, the Damascus Accident,.. Eric Schlosser, September 24,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connectome: How the Brain’s Wiring Makes Us Who We Are Sebastian Seung, May 27,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custer Larry McMurtry, March 23,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dept. of Speculation Jenny Offill, April 9,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duke: A Life of Duke Ellington Terry Teachout, March 25,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elemental Design Patterns Jason McC. Smith, November 8,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fairy Tales from the Brothers Grimm: A New English Version.. PHILIP PULLMAN, November 9,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finance Monsters: How Massive Unregulated Betting by a Small.. Howard B. Hill, December 14,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flash Boys: A Wall Street Revolt Michael Lewis, March 31,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Galileo’s Finger: The Ten Great Ideas of Science Peter Atkins, April 25,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gangster Squad: Covert Cops, the Mob, and the Battle for Los.. Paul Lieberman, January 4,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give War and Peace a Chance: Tolstoyan Wisdom for Troubled.. Andrew D. Kaufman, December 16,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Glittering Images: A Journey Through Art from Egypt to Star.. Camille Paglia, October 15,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Growing Vegetables West of the Cascades, Updated 6th.. Steve Solomon, December 16,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guesstimation 2.0: Solving Today’s Problems on the Back of a.. Lawrence Weinstein, November 7,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guide to: Learning Python Decorators Matt Harrison, February 6,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;His Dark Materials Omnibus Philip Pullman, August 3,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;House of Debt: How They (and You) Caused the Great.. Atif Mian, September 10,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Doctors Think Jerome Groopman, April 1,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Create a Mind: The Secret of Human Thought Revealed Ray Kurzweil, November 21,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to Make Sense of Any Mess: Information Architecture for.. Abby Covert, January 2,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the Light of What We Know: A Novel Zia Haider Rahman, October 14,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Influence Cialdini PhD, December 31,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instant: The Story of Polaroid Christopher Bonanos, January 12,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Mathematical Thinking Keith Devlin, October 23,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intuition Pumps And Other Tools for Thinking Daniel C. Dennett, May 13,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iron Curtain: The Crushing of Eastern Europe, 1944-1956 Anne Applebaum, November 7,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s Even Worse Than It Looks: How the American.. Thomas E. Mann, May 4,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Wayne: The Life and Legend Scott Eyman, March 31,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jonathan Swift Damrosch Leo, November 4,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karl Marx: A Nineteenth-Century Life Jonathan Sperber, April 19,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khrushchev: The Man and His Era William Taubman, October 20,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Life of Johnson, Volume 1 1709-1765 James Boswell, November 4,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mastering Python Regular Expressions (Community Experience.. Félix López, January 14,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mathematical Shenanigans Metin Bektas, January 19,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mating: A Novel (Vintage International) Norman Rush, August 29,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naked Statistics: Stripping the Dread from the Data Charles Wheelan, August 20,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Politics: A History of Political Thought: From Herodotus.. Alan Ryan, December 26,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the origin of species Charles Darwin, June 9,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Writing Well, 30th Anniversary Edition: An Informal Guide.. William Zinsser, March 25,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Summer: America, 1927 Bill Bryson, October 23,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Two Three . . . Infinity: Facts and Speculations of.. George Gamow, December 1,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orderly and Humane: The Expulsion of the Germans after the.. R. M. Douglas, December 26,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perilous Question: Reform or Revolution? Britain on the.. Antonia Fraser, December 25,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phi: A Voyage from the Brain to the Soul Giulio Tononi, November 8,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Professor Borges: A Course on English Literature Jorge Luis Borges, November 11,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;QED: The Strange Theory of Light and Matter: The Strange.. Richard P. Feynman, June 2,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reinventing Discovery: The New Era of Networked Science Michael Nielsen, November 2,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Revolutionary Ideas: An Intellectual History of the French.. Jonathan Israel, October 1,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Revolutionary Russia, 1891-1991: A History Orlando Figes, December 24,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Self Comes to Mind: Constructing the Conscious Brain Antonio Damasio, April 25,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shady Characters: The Secret Life of Punctuation, Symbols,.. Keith Houston, March 25,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Six Amendments: How and Why We Should Change the.. John Paul Stevens, April 21,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistics As Principled Argument Robert P. Abelson, September 10,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistics in a Nutshell Sarah Boslaugh, August 20,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stephen Vincent Benét, Collection (Thirteen O’Clock: Stories.. Stephen Vincent Benét, April 12,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structural Anthropology Claude Levi-strauss, December 1,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Aesthetic Brain: How We Evolved to Desire Beauty and.. Chatterjee MD, March 25,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The American Scene Henry James, September 21,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Art of R Programming: A Tour of Statistical Software.. Norman Matloff, January 9,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Basic Writings of John Stuart Mill: On Liberty, The.. John Stuart Mill, January 19,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Beak of the Finch: A Story of Evolution in Our Time Jonathan Weiner, August 5,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Book of Psalms: A Translation with Commentary Robert Alter, April 25,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Brothers: John Foster Dulles, Allen Dulles, and Their.. Stephen Kinzer, October 19,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bully Pulpit: Theodore Roosevelt, William Howard Taft,.. Doris Kearns Goodwin, February 4,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Coldest Winter: America and the Korean War David Halberstam, March 22,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Collected Works of Henry Adams (Unexpurgated Edition).. Henry Adams, January 19,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Collected Works of William James (8 collections of.. William James, January 21,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Discovery of France: A Historical Geography Graham Robb, November 10,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Essential Drucker (Collins Business Essentials) Peter F. Drucker, November 7,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The formation of vegetable mould through the action of.. Charles Darwin, April 8,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fractalist: Memoir of a Scientific Maverick Benoit Mandelbrot, February 28,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Garments of Court and Palace: Machiavelli and the World.. Philip Bobbitt, May 30,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Great Debate: Edmund Burke, Thomas Paine, and the Birth.. Yuval Levin, February 4,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Gutenberg Galaxy Marshall McLuhan, June 6,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Heart of Everything That Is: The Untold Story of Red.. Bob Drury, March 25,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The History of England, from the Accession of James II -.. Thomas Babington Macaulay, January 13,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Influence of Sea Power Upon History, 1660-1783 A. T. (Alfred Thayer) Mahan, December 7,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Innocents Abroad Mark Twain, July 23,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Language Hoax: Why the World Looks the Same in Any.. John H. McWhorter, January 12,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Meaning of Human Existence Edward O. Wilson, November 2,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Meaning of Relativity (illustrated) Albert Einstein, January 18,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Natural History of Selborne Gilbert White, November 18,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Noir Forties: The American People From Victory to Cold.. Richard Lingeman, December 21,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Number Mysteries: A Mathematical Odyssey through.. du Sautoy, August 26,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Odyssey of Homer Richmond Lattimore, April 19,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Parthenon Enigma Joan Breton Connelly, February 4,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and.. Charles Duhigg, January 9,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Red Badge of Courage Stephen Crane, April 12,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Revenge of Geography: What the Map Tells Us About Coming.. Robert D. Kaplan, October 23,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The River of Doubt: Theodore Roosevelt’s Darkest Journey Candice Millard, June 22,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Rolling Stones Discover America (Kindle Single) Michael Lydon, March 10,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Royalist Revolution: Monarchy and the American Founding Eric Nelson, January 16,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Secret History of Costaguana Juan Gabriel Vasquez, September 25,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Sense of an Ending (Borzoi Books) Julian Barnes, November 21,2011&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Shifts and the Shocks: What We’ve Learned-and Have Still.. Martin Wolf, January 19,2015&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Song celestial; or, Bhagabad-gîtâ (from the Mahâbhârata).. Anonymous, November 27,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Strange Library Haruki Murakami, December 1,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Theoretical Minimum: What You Need to Know to Start.. Leonard Susskind, May 20,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Theory of Moral Sentiments (Illustrated) Adam Smith, December 25,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Theory That Would Not Die: How Bayes’ Rule Cracked the.. Sharon Bertsch McGrayne, April 11,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The World Until Yesterday: What Can We Learn from.. Jared Diamond, January 30,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Those Angry Days: Roosevelt, Lindbergh, and America’s Fight.. Lynne Olson, September 9,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turing’s Cathedral: The Origins of the Digital Universe George Dyson, January 12,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unreliable Memoirs Clive James, August 27,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;War in Val D’Orcia: An Italian War Diary, 1943-1944 Iris Origo, May 10,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why Does the World Exist?: An Existential Detective Story Jim Holt, December 22,2012&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;World Order Henry Kissinger, November 2,2014&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Worldly Philosopher: The Odyssey of Albert O. Hirschman Jeremy Adelman, June 17,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Year Zero: A History of 1945 Ian Buruma, October 19,2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Medical Mind: How to Decide What Is Right for You Groopman MD, April 2,2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Felled by the law of the excluded middle</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/08/neutron/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/08/neutron</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You make a check list: timing, receiver, GPS, transmitter from the receiver to the detector, … you check everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1EpVhIM&quot;&gt;Data That Threatened to Break Physics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mediamacro</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/08/macro/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/08/macro</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;America didn’t need to make hard choices in the aftermath of crisis. What they needed, instead, was hard thinking — a willingness to understand that this was a special environment, that the usual rules don’t apply in a persistently depressed economy, one in which government borrowing doesn’t compete with private investment and costs next to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1KRBKGB&quot;&gt;Krugman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Family values, the conservative fallacy</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/08/family/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/08/family</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The family and the group are the essential social unit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Brooks in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/08/opinion/mothers-and-presidents.html&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dopamine cycles</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/07/slots/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/07/slots</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think the answer is, it’s okay to addict people as long as your business model doesn’t depend on it,” he said, as if finally finding the answer to a problem that had long seemed without a solution. “That’s the answer,” he added. “That’s the answer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nxt.fm/1P4n&amp;quot;10S&quot;&gt;Slot machines perfected addictive gaming. Now, tech wants their tricks The Verge via NextDraft&lt;/a&gt; by Andrew Thompson&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google, scrappy underdog</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/07/goog/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/07/goog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is something to be said about going for fat, complacent industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Herbert Hovencamp, speaking of &lt;em&gt;stodgy&lt;/em&gt; incumbent  wireless providers, quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1P4moUZ&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cat skinning</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/07/bitshort/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/07/bitshort</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having grown weary of cutting, pasting, copying, pasting repetitively to shorten links, I finally got around to writing a little snippet to do this. This works in Enthought Canopy Python 2.7.6  64-bit (with an annoying warning message about insecure connections) and in Python 3.4.3 Anaconda 2.2.0 (x86_64) with no message. You will need the free API token from bit.ly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# bitlyshort.py
# function to query bitly.com API with bitly provided access credential
# giving a long URL; function returns the bit.ly shortened url
# example
# result = shorten(&#39;http://www.example.com&#39;)
# result[&#39;data&#39;][&#39;url&#39;]

import requests

#YOUR BITLY PROVIDED CREDENTIAL: see http://dev.bitly.com/get_started.html&#39;
BITLY_GENERIC_ACCESS_TOKEN = &#39;abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz01234567890&#39;

def shorten(target):
	query_params = {&#39;access_token&#39;: BITLY_GENERIC_ACCESS_TOKEN,
					&#39;longUrl&#39;: target} 
	endpoint = &#39;https://api-ssl.bitly.com/v3/shorten&#39;
	return requests.get(endpoint, params=query_params, verify=True).json()

#print result[&#39;data&#39;][&#39;url&#39;]
# For troubleshooting, full contents of response.json() dictionary object
&#39;&#39;&#39;
{&#39;data&#39;: {&#39;global_hash&#39;: &#39;3hDSUb&#39;,
  &#39;hash&#39;: &#39;1cdxKEg&#39;,
  &#39;long_url&#39;: &#39;http://www.example.com/&#39;,
  &#39;new_hash&#39;: 0,
  &#39;url&#39;: &#39;http://bit.ly/1cdxKEg&#39;},
 &#39;status_code&#39;: 200,
 &#39;status_txt&#39;: &#39;OK&#39;}
&#39;&#39;&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>ACLU v. Clapper et al.</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/07/NSA/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/07/NSA</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1F1hr8X&quot;&gt;ACLU v. Clapper et al.&lt;/a&gt; is out today with a very good statutory analysis on whether Congress intended to make NSA bulk collection nonreviewable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-07-NSA.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>nice customs curtsy to great kings</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/veblen/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/veblen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;all canons of reputability and decency, and all standards of consumption, are traced back by insensible gradations to the usages and habits of thought of the highest social and pecuniary class—the wealthy leisure class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thorstein Veblen, &lt;em&gt;Theory of the Leisure Class&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Absolutism, qualified</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/vavreck/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/vavreck</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It appears as if the giant party difference in support for abortion under any and all conditions is an artifact of the way the typical abortion survey question is constructed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynn Vavreck in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1QnrJDY&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Vault  installation, Google campus, Kirkland, WA</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/vault/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/vault</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-06-vault.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Noblesse oblige</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/shaw/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/shaw</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is only in the middle classes, Stephen, that people get into a state of dumb helpless horror when they find that there are wicked people in the world. In our class, we have to decide what is to be done with wicked people; and nothing should disturb our self possession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lady Britomart, &lt;em&gt;Major Barbara&lt;/em&gt; by G.B.  Shaw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-06-shaw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Post-marital America</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/post-marital/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/post-marital</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;All politics is personal, very personal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Insofar as conservatives identify the erosion of the traditional family as a cause of civic disorder, the erosion is not limited to minority communities in Democratic cities. These trends are increasingly characteristic of white communities in red states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas B. Edson in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1IOdUMP&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Love Songs</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/lovesongs/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/lovesongs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The music of all creatures has to do with their loves, even of toads and frogs. Is it not the same with man?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoreau, &lt;em&gt;Journal&lt;/em&gt;, May 6, 1854&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Louie, Louie</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/louie/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/louie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Never mind if the obscenities were imagined—“Louie Louie” promised its listeners stronger stuff. As a member of the Flint Junior Woman’s Club argued, with admirable logic, in a 1965 letter to J. Edgar Hoover, it hardly mattered what the actual lyrics were when “every teenager in the country ‘heard’ the obscene not the copywritten [sic] lyric.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anwen Crawford in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1IO9Fk9&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Modern Trustbuster</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/bernie/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/bernie</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If an institution is too big to fail, it is too big to exist, and that is the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senator Bernie Sanders, quoted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1ReXwbH&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://careaga.s3.amazonaws.com/2015-05-06-bernie.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Better a bad ruler</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/06/badking/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/06/badking</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;than disorder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let us concede this much to the political order: to suffer kings patiently when unworthy, to hide their vices and to encourage their indifferent actions with our approbation – while their authority needs our support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montaigne, &lt;em&gt;Essays&lt;/em&gt; (M.A. Screech, &lt;em&gt;tr.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Parse date string</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/timezone/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/timezone</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# timezone.py
# exemplar
from datetime import datetime
from dateutil.parser import parse
from dateutil import tz

# The input isn&#39;t something that Python recognizes as a date
s = &quot;Mon Aug 15 21:17:14 GMT 2011&quot;     #start off with a string
d = parse(s)                           #convert it to a datetime object

# parse doesn&#39;t capture timezone information, so we need to specify
GMT = tz.gettz(&#39;UTC&#39;)                  #label for GMT
Beijing = tz.gettz(&#39;Asia/Shanghai&#39;)    #label for localtime

there = d.astimezone(GMT)              #express the datetime object in the GMT(UTC) zone
here = d.astimezone(Beijing)           #express it local zone

print(here)

print(there)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fun with stats</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/normal/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/normal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/statfact&quot;&gt;@StatFact&lt;/a&gt; -. The transform y = arcsine(sqrt(x)) can make proportion data approximately normally distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Land of the Free</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/jim-crow/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/jim-crow</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although the United States accounts for about 5 percent of the world’s population, it houses nearly 25 percent of the world’s prison population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1GY7Te7&quot;&gt;Hon.Jed S. Rakoff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bread and Circuses</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/gopfield/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/gopfield</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At this stage, the important thing to remember is that there are really two spectacles taking place: a high-stakes horse race for the Republican nomination, and a circus held on the infield of the track. Although the events run concurrently, and are ostensibly geared toward the same end, they shouldn’t be confused with one another. One is a serious political contest. The other is a sideshow, designed to amuse the spectators, give the media something to cover, and further the ambitions, varied as they are, of the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Cassidy in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nyr.kr/1zKpsPr&quot;&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>No dodgeball</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/dodge/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/dodge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think it’s important to understand that if this Court concludes that this issue should be left to the political process, what the Court will be saying is that the demeaning, second-class status that gay and lesbian couples now inhabit in states that do not provide for marriage is consistent with the equal protection of the laws. That is not a wait-and-see. That is a validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solicitor General Donald B. Verrilli Jr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nyti.ms/1KvEmcT&quot;&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Seven Pillars of Data Wisdom</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/datawisdom/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/datawisdom</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical functions produce measures, not analyses
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Being able to produce a measure or graph a function is not the same as understanding the result.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;See perennial best-seller &lt;em&gt;How to Lie with Statistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s even easy to fool yourself&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t assume that the data at hand necessarily is all you should be looking at.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;GIGO&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What the data &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; tell us&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finding the right ballpark&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quick and dirty but approximately right beats exactly wrong&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Teasing out the &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; questions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confirmatory Data Analysis
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is the theory that the data are supposed to test?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The null hypothesis and negative proof&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Finding the right statistical tool&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Interpreting the result&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Survey of Tests
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Parametric&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Non-parametric&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Tests to Models
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Parsimony as a guiding principle&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Types of predictive modelling&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dangers of overfitting&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sensitivity, edge cases, game changers and other qualifiers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reproducibility
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Checklists&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Standardized reports&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Version control&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Data snapshots&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Seeding&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presentation
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Underselling as career insurance&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Balance between bottom lines and supporting detail&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Importance of visualization&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keeping the gory details to technical appendices&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Confronting “so what?”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>BOOM!</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/05/boomers/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/05/boomers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wall-street-journal-warns&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/aging-baby-boomers-bring-drug-habits-into-middle-age-1426469057&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; warns&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers0.png&quot; alt=&quot;The shocking headline&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As the 76 million baby boomers reach late middle age, older adults are abusing drugs, getting arrested for drug offenses, and dying from drug overdoses at increasingly higher rates. The sharp increase in overdose deaths among older adults in particular is “very concerning,” says Wilson Compton, deputy director for the National Institute on Drug Abuse. The rate of death by accidental drug overdose for people aged 45 through 64 increased 11-fold between 1990, when no baby boomers were in the age group, and 2010, when the age group was filled with baby boomers, according to an analysis of CDC mortality data. That multiple of increase was greater than for any other age group in that time span. The surge has pushed the accidental overdose rate for these late middle age adults higher than that of 25- to 44-year-olds for the first time. Experts say the drug problem among older Americans has been brought on because a generation with a predilection for mind-altering substances is growing older in an era of widespread opioid analgesic abuse. Opioid analgesics are the drug most often involved in overdoses, followed by antianxiety medication, cocaine, and heroin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wsj.com/articles/aging-baby-boomers-bring-drug-habits-into-middle-age-1426469057&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; (2015-03-16) (&lt;em&gt;paywalled&lt;/em&gt;) by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zushaelinson&quot;&gt;Zusha Elinson&lt;/a&gt;, quoted by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/RjWvMu&quot;&gt;American Pharmacists Association&lt;/a&gt;. This &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/C1dQEk&quot;&gt;graphic&lt;/a&gt; (reproduced below) from the article illustrates the claims made in the headline and extract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stirring-the-teacup-to-make-a-tempest&quot;&gt;Stirring the Teacup to Make a Tempest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reporter, on Twitter as @&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zushaelinson&quot;&gt;ZushaElinson&lt;/a&gt;, describes himself there as focusing on criminal justice, which is also reflected in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/search/aggregate.html?KEYWORDS=Zusha+Elinson&amp;amp;SEARCHQUERY_PARSER=bylineAND&amp;amp;START_INDEX=21d&quot;&gt;WSJ bylines&lt;/a&gt;. But it is not lack of experience in science writing that troubles me with this reporting; &lt;em&gt;the facts do not show that the newly minted seniors have been drug abusers since high school and are disproportionately dying of drug overdoses even when they aren’t being arrested for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As defined in the article, boomers were born from 1946 to 1964. We mostly graduated from high school on schedule from 1964 to 1982. Currently, the youngest of us is 50 and the oldest 69. In 1990 we were 26 to 44; in 2000, 36 to 54; and in 2010, 46-64.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;busted&quot;&gt;Busted!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin with the claim in the graphic that &lt;em&gt;the rate for drug arrests for older adults (45-64) has increased dramatically as boomers have aged&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Compared to What?&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;What Was Happening?&lt;/em&gt; are two unanswered questions. From the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/aus9010.pdf&quot;&gt;Bureau of Justice Statistics&lt;/a&gt; we have answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the rates of drug arrests for &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; age group went up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the rates in 1990 include no boomers in the 45-64 year old bracket; the rates in 2000 include some but not all boomers; and 2010 is all boomers. The difference between the 1990 (black, solid) and 2010 (black, dotted) shows that compared to our immediate predecessors, born 1929-1945, boomers in their mid to late 40s had higher arrest rates, but the generational difference narrows greatly by the mid-50s and looks little different by 60. (Note, also, that the data series cuts off at age 64; too few seniors are busted for use to make the data very interesting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, from 1990 to 2010, the US population grew by 13.1%. The &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; of drug possession/use arrests grew by 80% and the &lt;em&gt;rate&lt;/em&gt; was 46% higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There were 80% more arrests for drug possession or use in 2010 (1,336,530) than in 1990 (741,600). Between 1990 and its peak in 2006, the arrest rate for drug possession or use increased 75% (figure 37). The arrest rate declined between 2006 and 2010, ending in 2010 at 46% above its 1990 level and at a level similar to those seen between 1997 and 2002.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/aus9010.pdf&quot;&gt;Bureau of Justice Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the actual numbers represented by these rates? For 2010, the 45-64 age bracket had about 153,000 arrests for drug possession/use. Out of a population in that bracket of 63.8 million. &lt;strong&gt;In other words, the “dramatic increase” reflects less than 1/4 of 1% of all boomers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for drug arrests as support for the supposition that boomer counterculture types have carried their habits into late middle age as reflected by arrest statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;teen-drug-use&quot;&gt;Teen Drug Use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boomers were druggies in their senior years of high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cited source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Johnston, L. D., O’Malley, P. M., Bachman, J. G., Schulenberg, J. E. &amp;amp; Miech, R. A. (2014). &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1Po1zP5&quot;&gt;Monitoring the Future&lt;/a&gt; national survey results on drug use, 1975–2013: Volume I, Secondary school students. Ann Arbor: Institute for Social Research, The University of Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;puts things in better perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Until 1978, the proportion of 12th graders involved in any illicit drug use increased steadily, primarily because of the increase in marijuana use (see Figures 5-1 to 5-4a). About 54% of the classes of 1978 and 1979 reported using at least one illicit drug during the prior 12 months, up from our first observation of 45% in the class of 1975. Between 1979 and 1984, however, the proportion who reported using any illicit drug during the prior year dropped by one to three percentage points annually until 1985, when there was a brief pause in the decline. In 1986 the decline resumed, with annual prevalence dropping significantly to 27% by 1992, exactly half the peak level experienced in 1979. As with marijuana, and largely due to marijuana, the annual prevalence of using any illicit drug then increased substantially during the relapse in the drug epidemic, from 27% in 1992 to 42% by 1997, after which it leveled for a few years before falling modestly to 36% by 2007. It remained at 37% in both 2008 and 2009, increased nonsignificantly to 38% in 2010, and then to 40% in 2011, where it remains in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-drug-use-currently&quot;&gt;What About Drug Use Currently?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/NSDUHresultsPDFWHTML2013/Web/NSDUHresults2013.pdf&quot;&gt;Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration&lt;/a&gt; gives this view&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, drug use goes down with age. There is a story about the difference between boomers and their immediate precedessors, but the story’s illustration points us toward the distant past&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to show boomers as &lt;em&gt;a generation with a prediliction for drugs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better question is &lt;strong&gt;what’s happening now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1ckNwOi&quot;&gt;2012 National Survey on Drug Use and Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boomers toke. Younger boomers toke more than older boomers. Leading edge boomers were fairly steady in their 2002-2012 intake. &lt;em&gt;And guess who’s playing catch-up?&lt;/em&gt; The immediate pre-boomers. (In the single digits, in all cases.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the same source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonmedical use of prescription drugs (basically painkillers and seditives) show a similar pattern, with the leading edge boomers converging on their slightly older cousins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cocaine, heroin, hallucigens and inhalents are also covered, but account for very little of the total usage of illicit drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buckets-got-a-hole-in-it&quot;&gt;Bucket’s Got a Hole in It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summary and graphic in the story give the most prominence to a sharp rise in drug overdose rates for the 45-64 year old group.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to notice is the use of overlapping categories: the red line for 45-64 and the black line for 55-74. Why? Cynically, it looks as if the tenor of the presentation is that whenever boomers join a line, rates shoot up. But if you look at the end points for the red and orange lines, there is no difference (less than 0.01 per 100,000) between the all-boomer and no-boomer groups. Also note that the boomers in the 70s had far lower OD rates than young adults since 2000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once more, there is more useful data from the same agency as the article cites. &lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1ckNUfO&quot;&gt;Chen, Hedegaard and Warner&lt;/a&gt; provide this view into the important category of opioid overdose deaths
&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/careaga/2015-05-05-boomers10.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other class of drugs involved in overdose deaths is benzodiazapens (Valium(TM) and its decscendants), usually in conjunction with opioids. Although cocaine and heroin overdoses can lead to death, the low usage in the boomer age group is expected to be reflected in relatively low numbers of deaths, as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-my-beef&quot;&gt;What’s My Beef?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the missing piece tying it all together&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The continuing increases in illicit drug use among adults aged 50 or older have important implications for substance use treatment and for the health care delivery system in general. The higher rates of use, coupled with the increasing size of the older adult population in the United States as the baby boom cohort ages, suggest a greater need for health care providers to consider illicit drug use among their older patients while also diagnosing and treating their health problems. Additionally, it has been projected that the number of adults aged 50 or older who would need alcohol or drug treatment would increase from 2.8 million (annual average) in 2002 to 2006 to 5.7 million in 2020 (Han, Gfroerer, Colliver, &amp;amp; Penne, 2009b). The results of the 2012 NSDUH are consistent with this projection, showing an estimated 4.0 million older adults currently needing substance use treatment, including 0.4 million persons needing treatment only for illicit drugs, 3.2 million needing treatment only for alcohol, and 0.4 million needing treatment for both alcohol and illicit drugs.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.usa.gov/1ckNwOi&quot;&gt;2012 National Survey on Drug Use and Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am growing cynical in my old age. I could easily imagine this piece as the opening salvo of a &lt;em&gt;Dump Social Security and Medicare&lt;/em&gt; campaign by the WSJ with the theme &lt;em&gt;they will just blow it on drugs, anyway&lt;/em&gt;. First we get it from our parents and now our kids. Karmic justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps. As a generation we have much to answer for. &lt;em&gt;But let us answer to the facts&lt;/em&gt;, which were mal-reported in the WSJ article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my gripes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stereotyping: everyone &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; that the early boomers had a reputation for “doing drugs,” so it follows that the generation born 1946-1964 actually &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; do drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of discrimination: there are drugs and there are drugs—lumping heroin and cocaine, which can be mortally dangerous with marijuana, which has always been harmful almost exclusively because it was forbidden tells us nothing useful about what challenges people moving into late middle age and old age face.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of context: drug use doesn’t exist in a societal vacuum
Missing elephants: 3.6 million adults over 50 need treatment for alcohol abuse; 400 thousand need treatment for drug abuse not including alcohol.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is already too easy to create clickbait in digital media. We need reporting from the old-line media, in its variety of world views, that does what it is supposed to do. Journalism: looking at the facts critically, not stretching them to decorate the headline. Copy editors have become an endangered species and I fear editors will soon follow. Reporters need both; I worry that they are getting neither.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The eternal *who*?</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/who/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/who</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We perceive the light reflected from ten million leaves and see the pattern &lt;em&gt;trees&lt;/em&gt;. We perceive the air on our skin or the dinner in our gut and feel the pattern &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;. But me should be &lt;em&gt;us&lt;/em&gt;, an ecosystem of bacteria and viruses to which we each are the primordial forest. Nor is industrial agriculture missing – we suppress or enhance fertility, apply pesticides and fertilizers and sprinkle fairy dust into our brains. Kill a bug, adjust pH, lower the hydraulic pressure, change the ratios of this or that to the other, we cultivate our East Eden gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the atheists among us believe in a version of the soul, even if it is not immortal. Beneath the Aristotelian accident lies a Platonic essence, our very own unique DNA. But that is a twinkling screen of flashing pixelish genes, ready to express an alternative manifestation at the drop of a protein. The chicken soup of our soul simmers in a cauldron that can, unexpectedly, serve out gazpacho or pho, dishes that nourish personae which our table companions can easily distinguish, even as we ourselves cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The eco-stews of our persons imagine themselves not only accurately to perceive, appropriately to categorize and purposefully to direct the incidents of their preparation. Dinner believes it has free will, constrained solely by personal legislation it enacts. Impinging on our own gustatory illusions are enablers to be propitiated (&lt;em&gt;forgive me, Father&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;pleeaase&lt;/em&gt;) or coerced (if worldly). We believe that nothing happens without personal agency, God’s or luck, that bitch goddess, or men and women and the lesser animals, such as dogs and children who we drape with moral vestments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because we impose a pattern, however, does not create an explanation, or even a meaning. Newton’s clockwork project has no scope in Planck’s probability  waves nor in our personal determinants whose calculation falls forever beyond Moore’s Law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a result, not a cause.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Church, state and billionaires</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/pope/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/pope</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But this, too, was a minor threat. Langone was simply threatening to withhold money. Now, as the pope prepares a major encyclical on climate change, to be released this summer, the billionaires are spending a great deal of their money in a direct assault on him. They are calling in their chits, their kept scientists, their rigged conferences, their sycophantic beneficiaries, their bought publicists to discredit words of the pope that have not even been issued: “He would do his flock and the world a disservice by putting his moral authority behind the United Nations’ unscientific agenda on the climate,” they say. They do not know exactly what the pope is going to say in his forthcoming encyclical on preserving God’s creation, but they know what he will not say. He will not deny that the poor suffer from actions that despoil the earth. Everything he has said and done so far shows that Francis always stands for the poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary Wills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1I6vdI0&quot;&gt;NYRB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Poke in the eye with a sharp stick</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/insult/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/insult</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If the intent is to insult, then is it really such a shock that people could feel insulted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1GKKRVo&quot;&gt;Vox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Brave New World</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/05/04/git-me/"/>
   <updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/05/04/git-me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marlow has been blogging going on a score years, first on an SGI Indy and a fractional T-1, then a virtual server. Such tedious overhead. Aristophenes be damned! Onto the cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It can never be just one lie</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2015/01/04/beliefs/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2015/01/04/beliefs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;unless you have an indefinitely extensible repertoire of ways to use your candidate belief (if that is what it is) in different contexts, it is not a belief in any remotely recognizable sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Dennett, &lt;em&gt;Intuition Pumps and Other Tools for Thinking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reynold's Number</title>
   <link href="http://technocrat.githup.io///2013/01/28/poem/"/>
   <updated>2013-01-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://technocrat.githup.io/2013/01/28/poem</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have no quarrel with time.&lt;br /&gt;
I float, flow, will sink, not sync.&lt;br /&gt;
Time herself has the indifference&lt;br /&gt;
Of a schoolboy’s secret crush,&lt;br /&gt;
We stand invisible in suspense&lt;br /&gt;
That perhaps the usual rules&lt;br /&gt;
Will be suspended, in our case,&lt;br /&gt;
And the surprise will be more time,&lt;br /&gt;
Time long after we weary of it&lt;br /&gt;
As we wearied of childhood and&lt;br /&gt;
Its fabled happiness of endless&lt;br /&gt;
August cut off from recess.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
